So now we have written a configuration for pretty basic use case of just creating and is a two instance
and deploying it into a subnet.
However, still, with this simple configuration, we have over 100 lines of code, all in one file,
right?
And the more resources we aired and the more complex our infrastructure gets, we're going to end up
with a huge file where we just have an endless scroll of different resources and outputs and data and
all of these components.
And obviously, now if you want to change something or adjust or find some resource definition, it's
going to be very difficult.
So in TerraForm, we have a concept of modules to make our configuration not monolithic like we have
here.
So everything in one file, but rather more modular, right?
So we basically break up parts of our configuration into logical groups and repackage them together
in folders, and these folders then represent modules, right?
For example, logical grouping of resources could be that every resource that we need in order to create
an ISA to instance, will be packaged in one module, right?
The instance itself, the IWC instance, the keep your creation because we need to keep here, for that
instance, to get the most recent image.
And also security group, because we're assigning the security group to eschew incidents, so this could
be one logical grouping of the resources, and we can call that a web server instance or just virtual
machine or whatever, and that will be basically a one module that we can reuse.
So if we're deploying an infrastructure with multiple instances, for example in different regions,
different availability zones, we can reuse that same web server module in multiple different places.
And the good thing is that whenever we define a module, we can pass in whatever parameters we want,
right?
We can parameter rise any values that we want to pass from outside dynamically.
And also, we can access the output of the module, right?
So whenever the resources get created that are part of a module, we can actually access the objects
and its attributes up towards, right?
So if you're familiar with programming, actually think about modules as defining functions, right?
So we write function once and we can reuse it in multiple different places in the configuration, and
we can pass in parameters to that function and we can decide what these parameters are going to be.
And we can return some values from the function right.
We can return an object with a bunch of attributes and modules make the configuration much cleaner.
It will make it easier to find the parts of configuration and resources that you have defined much easier
because they're not logically grouped.
One thing to note about modules is that whenever we are creating a module, it should be a proper abstraction
of our resources, meaning it doesn't make sense to just have a module for creating an IWC instance.
Just one resource.
Right?
Because then we just have an overhead of creating this whole new folder in a configuration file just
for one resource, right?
So it only makes sense to create a module when you want to group a couple of resources together into
a logical group, right?
As I said, creating a web server with all the configuration around it, like the firewall rules with
security group the key pair belonging to it, maybe the volumes that will be attached to it and so on.
Right.
Same thing with network configuration.
For example, when we create a VPC, it needs some inside.
It needs the internet gateway, the row table.
So all of this could be one module called VPC.
So that's important to note that you should actually be grouping several resources together so that
creating a module makes sense.
Now we can create our own modules, however, for very common use cases.
There are already modules created by TerraForm or other companies or individual developers that we can
re-use, right?
So they're not.
Everybody has to create their own VPC module or their own IEM module for IWC specifically and so on.
So for different technologies, not just IWC.
There are multiple modules.
So if we go to TerraForm Registry, this is actually where the list of providers can be browsed.
So we have seen E.W. in a bunch of other cloud providers, communities and so on.
So these are the providers, and right next to it you have a tip for modules.
If I click inside, I have a list of modules that we can reuse instead of having to create them ourselves.
Right?
And if we scroll here, we have a bunch of A.W. modules that groups basically resources together.
And we also have Google Cloud modules and so on.
And if we actually click in one of those, let's actually go with VPC module.
You have a very nice documentation of what this module actually creates or which resources it groups
together.
So this will be the Resources tab here that you can configure in this module, right?
So basically, it will create everything for you.
You just have to provide the parameters for all those resources and the parameters that you can provide
are defined in Inputs tab.
That you can pass in.
And here's a list of definitions, obviously, in most of the cases, you would just need a couple of
them and not all of them, obviously.
However, you have a possibility to define basically every single value of the resources defined in
that module.
And you also have the outputs.
So basically, this is what the resulting objects are resources that are creating using this module
return.
So you can use all of these values as an output, right?
For example, when you create VPC with subnets, you need the VPC, ID and subnet ID, maybe to create
other resources like ISA, to instance and so on.
And there will be in another module, right?
So you have to use the outputs of one module in another by referencing those IDs read.
And you can do that because those values will be exposed and you see those values and list of attributes
in outputs and you also have dependency.
Section and dependency basically describes whether this module contains or references other modules.
In our case, it doesn't.
So it basically creates everything from scratch with resources.
However, it depends on a provider of IWC, which is logical because it creates a bunch of IWC resources,
so it needs to have IWC provider.
And that means that whenever you are using that module and you do terraform in it, all the providers,
they're defined inside the module will be automatically installed, right?
So you don't have to define those providers in your main config file.
You just reference the module and we terraform.
You need the providers in the module gets installed.
And in other example, if we go into Ekeus, you see again description of what these modules actually
does and the resources that it groups together.
And here we have a longer list of providers that this module actually uses.
So under the hood, it uses all of those providers and resources from those providers.
And when we do terraform, you need all of them will be installed.
And if you want to use that module, you also have the basic usage example right here where you can
reference the source of the module like this.
Now, this is just a conceptual overview to understand what the modules are in that you can create your
own modules, but also reuse the ones that IWC or TerraForm created and reuse them to make it much easier.
And in the next part, we are actually going to see all of these in action.
We're going to be creating modules ourselves, you know, project, as well as using the existing ones
from the TerraForm registry.