So now we are going to create modules in our project, so basically we are going to take this main road
T.F. file, which basically has this list of resources that we're creating here, and we're going to
basically divide that into reusable modules instead of having one single file with all the configuration
in it.
So the first thing we're going to do is create a branch for modules.
And currently I am actually inside the deploy too easy to branch.
This is where we have the clean state with our parishioners and I'm going to create a branch from here.
And I'm going to call it module's.
So now we are in a new branch.
We can do whatever here without breaking the other branches.
And what I'm going to do now first before creating modules is to start cleaning up my mind or file.
So it is actually a best practice and a common way of writing terraformed configuration file to separate
the outputs into output or to file variables into a variable dot to file as well as providers into provider
TFR.
So you basically end up with just the resource definitions inside your mind or T.F. And that is actually
a common practice.
So we're going to do that inside our root folder, which is also a root module, as we already learned.
So by default, we already have a root module, which is the folder where we are creating the terraformed
configuration files.
So inside here we're going to create outputs dot t.f..
And all of the outward configurations will basically leave their.
And this is a nice way of separating and listing the similar resources in one location, because, as
I said, it may not have actually gets really long and you're just looking for output.
In order to modify something, you have to scroll through this list and find your output definition
between those resource configurations.
So it actually makes sense to list them into a separate file so you know where to find the outputs.
Another thing that also can be extracted are the variable definitions.
So we already have the variables file, which is too fast.
So now we are going to create variables dot t.f. and this is going to be the place for the variable
definitions.
Like this, and the good thing in TerraForm is that we don't have to link these files to each other,
we don't have to actually reference the variables T.F. and output stative from the main T.F. file,
because Terraformed knows that these files belong together and it kind of grabs everything and interprets
everything and links them together.
So we don't have to cross-reference them like we do in some programming languages, for example.
This is more straightforward here.
And as I said, we could also have providers file that holds all the providers.
However, we just have one here so we can actually leave it at that and actually have it in the main
file.
And now we have a structure which is again common.
When you write Terraformed Configuration that gives us Mendo tough file as well as output start to file
in variables or to file the names are just the standard.
You can actually name all these files, whatever you want.
These are just standards to name them like this.
And these three files actually also happen to be the common way of structuring modules.