So I'm going to create now a folder here called Modules
and Inside Modules, we are going to create folders for the actual modules so we can have, for example,
the Web server configuration.
Let's call it Web server module.
And then we can have a.
In the module's here, we can have another module and let's actually call it subnet.
So now we have prepared folders for two modules and each module will have its own main ATF output,
stative and variable stot T.F. files, so we can go ahead and create those three files in here.
And actually, I'm going to do it from a terminal because it's easier.
And if you're working also in a visual studio code like I am, you can actually have the terminal.
Window inside, instead of switching back to the operating system terminal, which opens up right away
in the correct folder of the project, and I'm going to create those files from here because it's just
easier.
So let's go to module's and.
To observer and inside here, I'm going to create my own doctor and I'm going to create Output's thought
T.F. And I'm going to create variables that T.F. And no, I'm going to switch to subnet and.
To the same basically main A.F. odd fruits and vegetables, and now if we expand those, there we go,
we have our module's structure, right.
These are now empty.
We don't have anything inside.
So we can start creating content in those files.
But this is actually the structure, which is also very straightforward and very logical in their form
of grouping together your modules and basically structuring your whole project.
So now when we create modules and configuration of these modules here, we can just reference them from
the main otf.
So we have an entry point configuration file, which is our root module, and then we have the children
modules inside that we can reference from the root.
So I'm going to close the terminal now and we have the structure now.
Now let's actually start extracting the configuration from here to individual reusable modules.
So first, let's actually move the subnets configuration to a module.
And there is one point about modules.
And when you're creating them, when you're creating a module, it actually should group a couple of
resources together.
So creating a module for one or two resources doesn't really make much sense.
So with a module, you should actually be grouping something together and making an abstraction of it
right.
To make a group of resources reusable because you already have the resource for subnet, right?
So creating a module just for one resource wouldn't make sense because you're not saving any code and
you actually have more overhead.
So just keep that in mind that when you're creating a module, you should actually group at least three
or four resources for it to make sense.
Right.
So in our case, we're going to do is that in our subnet module, we're going to actually extract the
whole configuration of the networking.
We're actually going to grab those three resources.
So basically the summit itself, the internal gateway and the default row table and its association
with Gateway.
And obviously, if we are creating a new round table, then we would have a subnet association with
it and we would also grab that along.
So in this case, I'm going to grab those three resources and I'm going to move them.
We're going to leave the VPC here and I'm going to move them in.
Subnet modules mean that T.F. and the way to actually use the module from another config file, in our
case, we're going to be actually referencing and using that module in the main otf of the root module
is actually to make it completely configurable because we have to pass in all the variables.
So basically all the values that are set here should be passed in by the configuration that is referencing
it.
So all of these values are going to be replaced with variables.
So the VPC is obviously we're going to call them VPC, DB and we're going to replace that in all the
occurrences like this.
The other parts here we have already parameterized, which is again a good practice, especially if
you want to modularize your project.
So we have already done that as well as here.
And we can substitute the value here as well as well as here.
We're referencing FBC, which is actually outside in the root module.
So I'm going to replace it with a variable and we're going to call it for those roads.
Well, that's code default rates, table ID, right.
We can leave the city block as is.
And this reference here actually anyway is Internet Gateway is.
Of a resource that exists in the same module, so we don't have to replace that through a variable because
we have that resource available in the same context so we can leave this as is we have to replace these
ones because we don't have the VPC reference inside here.
It's defined outside.
So we have to pass that as a variable so we can leave all the IP addresses as well as we can leave the
reference to a resource that exists in the same module.
Great.
So now we have to define all those variables inside that module in the variables dot t.f..
So all this variable definitions must actually be in that file, right.
Because having those values available in variables, the ATF doesn't actually work for us.
Right.
It has to be in the same module.
So I'm actually going to copy some of these variables.
Let's actually see what we need.
We need the subnet cider block.
So I'm going to.
Copy that in here.
We also need available to Zone and prefix.
I'm going to grab both.
And copy it here, I actually cut the Senate side are blocked because we only need it in the subnet
module, but if anybody's on in and prefix, we actually need it for the Web server as well.
So I'm going to leave it here as well.
And we have two new variables, which are VPC, ID and default round table ID.
So we're going to create those as well.
And I'm going to close it,
so now we have all the variables that we're referencing in the subnets configuration defined in the
modules variables dot file.
So now that we have the configuration as well as the variables defined, how do we actually use the
module or how do we reference it from another configuration file?
And the way we do that is actually using a module keyword.
So we're going to write a module and then we're going to call this module something that we want.
So let's actually call it my app dash subnet and we're going to create a blog.
And now here we're going to need a couple of attributes.
The first one is the source of the module.
So where is this module actually living?
Right.
And the source in our case is just the location or path to the folder of our module.
And that is modules slash subnet.
So we are telling TerraForm, we're defining a module here.
And this is the name that we just decided to give it.
And the actual code or configuration of the module actually leaves inside a folder called Modules Subnet.
So TerraForm will find the configuration files here and this will be basically our module.
And once the source is defined now, we actually have to pass in all those variables that we defined
in here, actually.
Right.
So the values to those variables need to be provided when we are referring to module.
So if you're familiar with programming languages, think of it like defining a function with a bunch
of parameters and then calling that function in here by passing in those parameters one by one is values.
Right?
This is exactly what we are doing here.
So let's actually set those variables one by one.
So previously we had all these variables or some of these variables already set in the way we provided
values to those variables was actually through terraformed or T.F. versus file.
Right.
This is how we were actually passing the or setting those variable values.
Now, since we made it into module, we have to define them in the module section.
So let's actually set them one by one.
So we have the subnet side block and now the subnet side or block value.
We can actually provide it either by hard coding it like this or we can also reference it from the TFN
file, just like we did before.
So instead can do.
However, this reference actually comes from the variables.
The ATF in the main module and I have actually deleted that from here.
However, if you want to reference it from Mendota in the root module, we actually need that variable
definition also in the variables dot to file in that module.
So I'm going to add it back so that we can reference it.
So basically now what we're doing is we're referencing a variable called Subnet Seiter block that has
to be defined in the same module where this means T.F. is so we have variables or T.F. for that.
So it has to be declared here.
And those variables then are set through the terraformed T.F. varas file where we are just providing
the values for all those variables.
So this is how it works.
We have the values, the actual values defined here that are set as values of the variables defined
in this file.
And then we're passing on those values.
In this case, the subnet site or block to the module subnet in here, which is also grabbing those
values through variable references, which also have to be defined in the variables that have.
So we kind of have the hierarchy of variables and the references.
And this actually makes sense when you have complex set up and complex infrastructure.
And to make it modular, even though it seems like an overhead for a small setup now and the same way
we're going to actually reference all the other values that our module requires.
So basically, all of these values here and as I mentioned previously, if we are going to provide them
as variables ourself or we're going to reference them as values here, they need to be defined in these
variables that T.F. also.
So let's see the second variable.
Which is a zone that's also referenced it like this, also from the tier from tier first, while we
also have environment prefix, which is also stated here, and then we have the VPC Edem, which we
can actually access from the resource because we have the VPC resource defined in this module so we
can do this.
So basically, as you see, even though we have extracted a module of our subnet, the syntax and the
concepts actually stay the same.
So we didn't have to change how we reference the existing resources or how we reference the variables,
file values and so on.
It's just that we have created another level of hierarchy within our project and finally we have default
Rhodes Table Edem, which we can also reference.
From the VPC.
And the attributes, as we saw previously, is Deverall table idea of the VPC object.
So this way we're actually setting all the values.
So these are the attribute names that we define ourselves.
This could be anything that we want.
Let's actually close this off and right here.
So basically, whatever we name the variables, they are going to be the attribute names of the module
and the names that we're going to be setting here.
And as I said, the values can be either hardcoded.
So this could be a string with actual block or in our case, we're referencing the T.F. Vase values,
or we can reference it from the resource object like we're doing for VPC, ID and default row table.
And one thing that I forgot to do here is actually in the source.
If we are referencing a module using a relative path, so basically relative to the main file, then
we have to specify like this.
So we have to say current directory.
That's what DOT is for modules subnet.
So without this we will actually get a warning.
So let's fix it right here.
So we have this module declared here, however, because we have extracted all these resources, including
the subnet resource, to its own module, the references are actually broken now.
So if I scroll to easy to instant's.
Which is referencing the subnets right here.
This will not work because we don't have a resource called Illawarra's subnet with this name defined
in this module.
Right.
This resource is actually defined in another module.
And we cannot access a child module resource like this.
We can only access it through module definition.
Right.
So we actually need to fix those references first so that this code can work again.