And now is a next step, let's actually extract this whole configuration that is related to the Web
server, also to each separate module.
So basically we have the instance itself.
We have the key here that is being created.
For the instance we have the aim, I query from the US, which is also relevant for the instance, and
we have the security group, which also configures the firewalls for the instance.
So basically, again, you see a pattern here.
We have for resources or three resources and one data that are all needed in order to create an instance.
Right.
So they basically all directly relate to that specific instance.
So it makes sense to group them and make them into own module.
So I'm going to copy all of this.
And in the website Remaindered TAF, I'm going to paste it in and we're going to go through the same
changes.
So basically we need to fix the references to all the values here, like the VPC ID that is not available
in this mean T.F. But rather has to be said from outside.
So far, vpc id we have a variable for my IP already here.
We can leave all of these fixed coded values if they don't change or we can also promontories them if
we want to pass in different values.
So for example, if we want to be able to decide which operating system image should be used for that
instance, we can also extract this value actually here.
So let's make it into a variable as well.
Image name, let's say, and we are going to need to pass that on from outside.
We also have the Saraki and the public relocation is already parameterized, we have the instance Taib
also is a variable and for Aimi we are actually referencing the data which is fine because we have the
data in the same configuration.
So that reference works fine.
Now, we don't have access to the module anymore because this module is actually defined outside.
So we're going to parameterize that as well.
So we are going to do for subnet Edem.
We also have the default security group ID default is G IP.
What else do we have?
We have the availability zone as a variable.
The key name is again a resource in the same module.
So we can reference it like this just like before.
And finally we have the entry script on S.H..
Right.
And this is basically a file that we are executing on the server.
We can leave it outside and reference it using a relative path or actually it makes sense to have it
in the same folder.
So I'm just going to move it to Web server and we can reference it like this is previously.
So we have parameterized most of the stuff.
Again, if you want to hardcoded some of the values because, you know, they are always going to stay
basically the same, then you can leave them hardcoded if you want to provide value for them, dynamically
different values like image, name, et cetera, then you can set them as variables.
And then we're going to have to pass those variables when we declare the module.
So we have parameterized all the values we need and now it's time to declare all those variables in
the variables.
Start T.F. File.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So let's start from the top variables.
T.F. Here variable VPC ID.
We can actually specify the types for all the variables as well description.
But I'm going to leave those configuration empty for all variables.
I'm just for simplicity.
So my IP.
Then we have in prefix.
We have the image name.
Public key location.
So we have a lot of.
Fellows here to set.
Which is actually very typical for module's, because you're usually abstracting away a bunch of resources
or packaging together a bunch of resources, and they have all these attributes, so modules usually
end up having a huge list of parameters that you can pass in.
So I think we have said all the or declared all the variables here.
If we missed something, we basically know it when we execute terraformed terraform.
So I think we have the whole list declared here.
So, no, actually, it's time to reference that module in the main dot file.
So just like we did with the subnet, we can reference it here.
Say my app.
Server.
Again, we have the source, which is module's web server, and then we have all these variables that
we need to set.
So I'm actually going to copy all this.
Just to save time, and obviously we don't need this variable.
OK, so I have removed the variable and curly braces so we can actually go ahead and set those values.
And let me actually check which of those variables I have already defined here so that I can reference
them.
So these are the variables defined in the root module.
So it means that I can reference them here using four dots and the variable name.
Right.
So let's assign the values one by one.
First of all, the ID we can reference from here.
Let's actually copy this one.
So we have the in my app, we have the variable defined here, so I'm going to reference it, then we
have the end prefix, which I'm also going to reference.
And this is also a good thing, because if you have same variable used in many modules like environmental
prefix or Liberty Zone, you don't want to hardcoded them multiple times in module declaration.
But if you reference it like this, you have to define its value, just the ones in the TerraForm Force
file.
And if it changes at some point, then you can just change it here and don't worry about fixing it in
a bunch of different places.
So that's why it's actually good to always reference values through variables and having them defined
in these two four words file.
And let's continue.
We have the image name, so let's define that here.
So I'm going to add this.
Is it value?
Public key location, we already have that instance type, we have that as well.
And now here we have the subnet I.D. reference again and the same way as we referenced it, when we
had to use it directly in the resource, we can do it exactly the same way.
So basically using module DOT, the module name DOT, the name of the outputs.
She's subnet.
That's actually close, this one.
OK, I have too many things open, right, so name of the output and the ID, the next one, we have
default security group ID, which let's actually go back to our Web server.
We don't actually need to reference it as a variable because.
We can reference it from the resource, so we have the default security group resource right here so
we can just reference it using the resource type and name.
And so that means that I'm going to remove that from here as well, and we don't need to define it in
the module.
So one less variable and then we have availability zone and the prefix.
So both are actually variables with the same names.
So I can just copy that.
And there you go.
We're referencing basically every value, either using a var or module or a resource name, which is
a good practice because we're not hard coding any values and now we have to make sure that all those
values are actually defined in our turf wars file.
So we have it right here.
Let's actually close it and let's go through them.
We have my IP defined in here.
We have the prefix, we actually have it twice.
OK, great.
So we have the prefix we need to set Veli for image name, we don't have it yet and this is going to
be the previous value that we had defined.
So now, for example, if you wanted to use another image, we can change this name or this regular
expression in here.
Then we have the public key location, which is already set here.
Then we have instant.
Stip also said we have subnet ID, which we're referencing from a module and we have the ability zone,
which is also said.
So that's great to have all the values that we need.
So now we are actually ready to execute this.
So let's go back to our terminal and know if I do it here for a plane.
There you go.
We should see a warning from terraformed.
That module is not installed because as I mentioned previously, whenever we create a new module or
we make changes to already initialized or installed module, we have to run terraform in it again.
So let's do terraform in it.
And there you go.
Now, my app server module is getting initialized.
Great.
So now let's do TerraForm Plan, which will also tell us whether we have any errors in the configuration
and also show us the changes it will make to our existing infrastructure.
And there you go.
We already see some errors.
First of all, we have this error here because we forgot to remove a wrong reference from the output
STF So this outputs ATF belongs to the root module and it actually doesn't have access to any of those
resources anymore because we have moved them into separate modules.
Right.
We don't have those resources declared in here.
However, if we still want to output that as a result of execution, what we could do is reference those
values through the module component.
So let's say we don't care about the image idea, but we want to output the public IP address of the
easy to instance.
So what we're going to do is do module.
Then we need the name of the module, which we called my observer,
and they will basically give us access to the module and inside the module, we need to access the E,
C to instance.
And as you learn previously, in order to access the resources and its attributes from a module, we
have to output that object first in the outpost otf of that module.
So right here, we're going to do output's, let's call it instance and a value will basically be.
Instance know is instance the type, and we have the server and let's actually put the whole object,
so this will give us the whole instance with all of its attributes and then we can decide which one
we want to access.
So we are now exporting the instance using the instance output, and this is how we can actually access
it.
And here so this is the module.
This is the output name and we need the public IP attribute, so again, gives us access to the whole
etc. instance because we have exported it or I'll put it here.
And then we can access any attribute on that object and the second warning we got was about the entry
script or S.H. it looks like on line 60 where we're referencing the file, it cannot find that file
in its location.
So let's fix that.
And the second error, which is referencing the entry script file, we can actually easily fix it by
just moving that entry script outside that module.
So basically having it in the root module will fix it.
So now let's actually do terraform plint again.
And there you go, terraform, refresh the state, it compared the current state with the desired state
and this is the output, so let's grow up all the way.
So first of all, the BBC and Summernats are already created, so they will not be created again.
However, here we have security group, an existing one that will be destroyed, and my service, as
well as SFH key and new resources will be created in their place.
So security group will be created as well as the server itself.
And the key here.
And we also have change in the output, which is basically that Aimi ID will be removed as an output.
However, we are going to see a new public IP of easy to.
So now let's actually apply this.
And as you see from the error message itself, we have a duplicate keep here, which seems like a timing
issue because the SSA key was destroyed or removed like other components, and probably the new one
was created too soon.
So if we execute or reapply this, it should actually work.
And whenever we actually get an error in terraform, something called a crash log file gets created.
And this basically gets auto generated by TerraForm and it it gets created inside the root module.
So if you click inside, you see basically the logs of failures of terraform apply so you can see a
full lock here.
So Crestone log is actually one of the files that we also want to ignore and not check in.
So in the Dawngate ignore, we just going to add these crash log files.
So just as a side note, so ignore crash logs and let's do this.
And as you see, it's great out as an ignored file.
So let's head back to our console.
Let's actually check our interview as we have one.
Syria, which is terminating otherwise, everything is clean.
So I'm going to try to execute this again and see what happens this time.
And there you go.
We have two resources that were created, and now if we go back to our management console, there you
go.
We have one instance which is running as well as the keep here God created.
And we have the public IP address printed out here as previously, since we're accessing it through
the module and all is actually try to access into it.
So we're inside of the server and we can actually now validate that the entry script shall script also
ran successfully.
And since our entry script basically installs Docker, we can just validate that there is Docker already
installed on the server.
So I'm just going to do Docker version.
And there you go.
We have Docker Command available, so the scripts ran successfully as well.