Great.
So we basically created a structure in our TerraForm project, which is actually a structure, a common
standard way of structuring your TerraForm project.
We have created modules where we logically grouped similar resources that belong together into own modules
while still creating one of the resources outside.
We also learned how to use those modules, how to reference them and pass on different values that we
configured inside the modules themselves, as well as we learn how to reference the resource objects
inside the modules itself, using this module reference and then basically just access any attributes
of their object.
So our project looks great.
We have all the resources parameterized, which is actually a best practice.
So all the values are set in one place in the TFN file.
So if something changes, we just adjust in one place and we don't need to worry about adjusting the
rest of the configuration.
And as the last part, we can just commit everything to get let's actually see the status of all the
changes.
There you go.
We have modules and we have basically adjusted everything.
So I'm going to add all the changes.
Let's commit modularize terraform project.
The reform push will give us said upstream for our branch, which doesn't exist remotely yet, and we
can just push the whole branch and there you go.
We have our module configuration in the remote branch, if you want to reference it later.