Now, what we're going to do as the next step is create a good repository for our TerraForm project,
so whatever changes we make to artier from configuration, we can actually work with the repository.
So we have a history of the changes and also other team members can check out the code and work on the
same project as well.
So first of all, I'm going to go to get Lip UI and here I'm just going to create a new blank project.
Let's call it TerraForm
Learn.
So inside the company will be probably a private repository.
I'm going to make it public so that others can access my project here.
The remote repository exists in Ditlev, so we can connect our local project to the remote repository,
so it means that we are going to make it into a good project.
So even here, I mean the root folder of the project.
So we're going to do it in it.
And this will initialize an empty repository.
And what we're going to do is we are going to connect it to the remote.
Right.
Put an existing folder.
So you already have a existing repository.
So our existing code and what you need to do is get remote at origin and it will point to the remote
project, which is this one right here.
So I'm going to execute it.
And now if I do get status, it tells me that I have to check in all these code.
Right now is the next step before we actually check in everything that we have.
We're going to create a get ignore file because the thing is, we don't need to check all of this information
or all of these files to the repository.
Some of the files shouldn't be checked into the repository.
And let me create a kit, ignore file, and then we're going to see what these files are.
So get ignored.
So the first thing we're going to ignore in the changes.
So what we're not going to check into the repository is this DOD terraform folder here.
This basically just stores the providers that are installed locally.
So it doesn't have to be part of the code when you do terraform in it.
This will be downloaded on your computer locally.
So we don't have to check that in and we're going to ignore it.
Let's actually add a comment here.
Local terraformed directory.
And we are going to.
And we're going to ignore the whole folder.
Another thing we want to ignore is not chicken is terraformed state because obviously terraformed state
is a generated file that gets updated every time we do terraform a play.
And this is a local state when you are playing around and doing a play.
So we're going to ignore this one as well to our form states file or files.
We have two of them.
We have the current state and we have the previous one.
So we're going to ignore both of them.
So let's do.
He stayed so every file with this extension as well as dot pick up.
What we also going to ignore is the terraform variable files, and the reason why is that, as I said,
terraformed variables are basically a way to give users of terraform, maybe other team members a way
to set the parameters for the configuration file.
And these parameters will be different based on which environment you are using.
So changes depending on the environment.
And also these variables file may actually contain some sensitive data, could be password, private
keys of the users themselves.
So, for example, you may be pointing to your private SSL keys or some certificates and other secrets
could be different for different team members.
So we're going to ignore the terraformed variables file so each user of this reform project should have
their own copy locally.
So they're able, let's say to your variable files may include sensitive data,
T.F. Vast.
Right.
So all the files that are ending with dotted bars extension.
And as I saved this configuration, you see that those ignored files or folders actually became great.
So they're automatically removed from git def.
So basically it just ignores any changes made to these files and they're not displayed as something
to be checked in.
So now if I do get status.
There you go.
You see all these files that we ignored are not on the list here, but we have to ignore file.
So we're going to check these remaining stuff in basic.
We just have maned or T.F. And we have terraform look files.
Right.
And this one should be checked in, actually, because this is a list of providers that you have installed
locally with their versions and this should be in the repository.
So we're going to add all of these.
We're going to do initial commit.
And now if we go back to the repository for the first push, we're going to do upstream Origin Master.
So we're pushing to Master Branch.
From local to and you only have to do it first time when you're pushing the branch changes for the first
time to any branch for the very first time after that, you can just do it push.
So we have pushed our changes repository.
If I refresh it.
There you go.
You see three files checked in here so we can now work in the repository and make changes, create branches
for trying out different use cases, etc..
So we have all the history in here.