Now, creating the keep here, actually, for SSA pushing into the server is not very optimal if we
have to do it manually all the time, right.
If we have to go to the iTunes console and then we have to create it here and then download it locally
and copy it to the sausage folder and said it's stricter X's and so on.
So it's all a lot of manual work still.
Right.
So how can we actually automate this using terraform so that we don't have to do any of this manually?
So let's go back to the config file and I'm actually going to create a resource code eight of us key
here.
So we're going to create the key here using terraformed instead of doing it manually and let's call
it this is a key.
And we have two attributes here, we have the key name, which is the name given here, let's call it
server key to make it different from this one.
And the second attribute is public key.
So basically, it means that we need a public key so that eight of us can create the private public
key peer out of that public key value that we provide.
Now, the question is, where do we get the public key now?
Locally on your machine, you can actually create your own private public key peer.
Right.
And that local keeper is actually located inside the ISS each folder.
So instead, it's a search.
We have something called I.D., RSA, and then we also have any RSA pop.
So this is the public key and this is the private key.
Right.
So if you don't have this key pair or if you don't have this, each folder at all can very easily be
generated, including this is each folder by using by using a comment called S.H. Key, Jane.
So if I execute this, it will basically create a cube here locally and you will end up with the same
SSL folder or dot S.H. folder and these two keys inside and ID RSA part is actually the public key that
we need as a value right here.
So once you generate that key or if you already have that available locally, what it can do is you
can basically just grab that value by just outputting it in the console like this and then just grab
the whole output, including the email at the end.
And pasted in here is a string.
So it starts with DSH, RSA and it ends with your email.
So basically the whole string will be a value in here and that is going to be your public key.
Now again, this is something that you probably don't want to check into the repository or something
that each user of this configuration file will basically want to override locally or set themselves
because every user will have their own public key.
So either we can extract it into a variable and every user of these terraform project can configure
it locally in their own variable file copy so it can be public key or my public key
so we can reference it here and then define the value right here.
There will be one option or we can also reference the file location.
So we don't have to actually provide the string here.
We can just add it to the file location, which makes sense because maybe you don't want to have the
whole content as a string here.
So what we can do here is dollar sign and then we have.
File.
And this basically.
We'll read from a file, and this is going to be location of the file, and again, maybe this location
is different for every user of the project so we can actually make this configurable.
Let's do a public key location.
So this is how you can use file or read from a file to set a value in terraform.
So we have to define this variable
and we're going to have to set it right here.
And this could be an absolute path.
So in our case or in my case, I can set it to.
This and this will be basically the file or the public key location on my laptop and basically each
team member or user of this project can configure this location and filename themselves.
So we make it more generic and reusable for everybody else.
Great.
So now this will basically create the keeper and we can reference this.
Keep here in the IWC.
Easy to instant's now.
Right.
So we have the old here is a reference here.
Now we can update it and set it to the new one.
And instead of hard coding it, we can just reference the key name from the resource.
So let's do.
This is a chicken and the egg tribute and no, let's actually do terraformed plan going to exit from
the server and let's do terraformed plen.
And this is actually very helpful if you make changes to existing resource and you want to know, first
of all, if your configuration is valid, so validate that, first of all.
And second of all, you want to know whether that resource needs to be recreated.
Right.
So it means that whether the attributes can actually just be replaced or does the whole resource need
to be recreated?
And in our case, we see that the server must be replaced.
So it has to be recreated.
So the old one will be removed and a new instance will be created in its place.
And the reason is because we're changing the key and it is not something that we can just exchange in
a running instance.
In this way, TerraForm knows that it needs to recreate the resource.
And we also see a warning here for our Syntex, which basically says that.
The interpellation, which is a fancy word for just combining the string and variable into one string,
basically is deprecated for specific cases where you don't have a string inside, that you only have
the variable.
So we also have a suggestion we can actually fix that warning by removing this whole bit here and leaving
this expression, which actually is cleaner so we can validate that as well.
So this is also interpolation.
However, here we have variable and a string, so we don't get a warning for that.
However, here we only have a variable reference and we're calling this file method.
So no interpolation needed here.
So let's actually run Terfel plan again.
And great, so the warning is gone.
There was a small Syntex issue and this is the same output.
So now we can actually do terraform play.
Or proof.
And let's actually refresh this, and as you see, our previous AC2 instance is shutting down and a
new one will be created in its place and it was destroyed and now a new server is getting created.
Let's refresh it again.
The old one is terminating, a new one is getting initialized.
So let's wait for that to finish and then we'll be able to S.H. into it.
And while we're waiting, we can actually add another output in here that will print us the public IP
of the instance that we just created.
So let's call it easy to public IP.
And we can get the value from.
In this instance, my server, and now we need the attribute name of.
Public IP and like previously, we can also do terraform.
Stage show.
And we can just print out the attributes of Isleta instance, and one of them is public IP and this
is what we need.
And let's save it for the next.
Appli.
Let's refresh it again, this initialised, so now we can S.H. into the server now in this case, we
use our own public key and associated that with the easy to instance so we don't have a dot pen file,
actually.
Right.
So how do we assess into this instance?
Let's.
Go to the terminal and do a secich.
Easy to user, and let's actually grab the public IP of that instance.
Like this, so now we need a private key, just like the pimp file that will allow us to S.H. into the
server and the private key.
Of the private public pier that we use is actually.
This one, right?
So we used I.D. or as a dot pub is a public key and it's Perre because it's a public private Kippy,
right.
So we have those two parts.
So we're going to use the private key to S.H. into the server.
And the private key happens to be this one right here.
And this will basically allow us to assess each.
And there you go.
This is the new instance that we just created.
However, let's actually exit and show you a shortcut for this now, because this is actually a default
location for the private key.
So whenever you do, S.H., this will be actually set as a default.
We can just leave this out.
And just to S.H..
And there you go.
We can still access into the server because.
These two are actually equivalent comments, so you don't have to even specify, so that's actually
one advantage of using the local your own public private key pair.
And again, we created a server and we were able to access into it.
So that means we can actually clean up and remove the server, keep here Dot Pym that we downloaded
because we don't need it anymore.
We can just use our own keep here.
So I'm just going to remove it.
Let's do yes.
And let's actually check that it has been removed and there you go.
The type completion cannot find the file, so it is not there.
And we can actually remove the previous key here as well.
We don't need that anymore and delete.
Great.
So we have automated the part of creating the server key, the S.H. key for the U.S. to instance, also
we terraform and there is a big a really huge advantage in automating most of this stuff with TerraForm
and doing as little as possible manually or in ideal case, doing nothing manually.
And the clear advantage of that is, first of all, when you're creating a lot of resources and you
end up creating some of it and configuring some of this stuff manually, there is a high chance that
you forget about these things when it's time to clean up the resources.
Right.
So when you delete everything using tear from destroy, you may actually forget to delete this stuff
that you created manually or configured manually in other cases if you want to replicate the environment.
Right.
So you created a development environment and then you want to use the same term configuration to create
a staging environment.
Again, if you created some of the parts manually, you have to remember and do the same thing on the
staging environment because they are not part of the config files.
And this means that you have to document that somewhere and you have to know the steps and remember
or if someone else is doing, you have to tell them and share that knowledge with them.
Right.
So there's a clear advantage of automating and basically writing all the code that possible inside the
terraform configuration file and not doing and configuring stuff manually.
So that is actually a best practice, a preferred way of doing it with a clear benefit of basically
saving time and doing all these things like creating keep here, here and then downloading the file
and then saving the file somewhere and so on, because doing stuff manually usually takes more than
just configuring it once and then applying it as many times as you want.