Great.
So we have an easy to server configured, we have all the networking around it configured.
However, there is nothing running on the server yet, right?
We have no docker installed.
We have no docker containers running.
So basically the server is empty.
Now, we can, of course, S.A.G. into the server.
We can install Docker on it, we can start docker container and so on.
However, again, we want to automate as much of a work as possible and we don't want to do manual work
and we want that configuration to be a part of the code.
Right.
We want that to be in the file that we can execute as many times as we want.
So with the terraformed, there is a way to execute commands on a server, on ISATOU server in this
case at the time of creation.
Right.
So as soon as the instance is ready, we can define a set of commands that terraform will execute on
the server.
And the way to do that is using an attribute called user data.
So user data is basically like an entry point script that gets executed on is it, for instance, whenever
the server is instantiated.
Right.
So this is the initial script and we can provide the script actually using multiline string and we can
define it using the syntax.
So we have this block.
And inside that blog, we can actually define the whole Shell script, right, just like you would write
it in a normal script file, right.
In a bashful and since it's Linux, we can write Besch comments.
So exactly like you would executed on the server itself with Linux commands the same way.
We're going to write the commands in here.
So we're going to start with a shebang, first of all, so that it's a best script and then we're going
to start the comments.
Now, obviously, you have to know these commands.
You have to try this out to make sure that they work.
But I have tried them out, so I'm just going to write them.
They're actually not very difficult.
So what are we going to do is on our fresh new server, we are going to do youm update.
So we're going to update all the packages, the repositories first.
And since it's not an interactive mode, we can't confirm the input.
Right.
We're going to do automatic confirmation.
That's what minus Y stands for.
So I'm inside the server now.
So basically you can check which package manager you have.
We have here in Amazon Linux image.
And when you do update, you get this prompt here.
Right.
So we have to confirm whether to continue or not.
So in this case, we click.
Yes.
And this is basically the same confirmation that we are writing.
So this confirms and then we can do again sudo yum install Docker.
So after the update, we're going to install Docker so that we can execute Docker commence.
And once the doctor is installed, we have to start it and we can do it using system control.
Start Docker.
And these are all Suda comments, because easy to a user doesn't have permission to install stuff,
so we're going to have to do that with Stuto and then we want to execute documents without Suda comment.
Right.
And for that, we're going to need to add the issue to a user, to Tokura Group, and we're going to
do that using user mode or modifying the user, adding it to a group.
That's what it stands for.
Group name, Docker, user name, easy to user.
This is the user that we are SSA checking into as this is a default Linux user that we have available
on this Linux images.
Right.
So as I said, this command will basically at our user in Docker group, and that will make it possible
for us to run Docker commands on that server without.
So now we can do Docker run.
And as I mentioned, we can start a very simple engine X container on port eighty or eighty eighty on
the host and Bindy to Port 80 on Ingenix and this will be resupplied.
So these are the commands we want to execute right away after server is created.
And this will make Engine X basically available on the server.
And we are saving manual effort for SSA into the server, installing all this running container and
so on.
So this should all be executed automatically by terraformed.
So let's save it.
And now let's actually do terraform plan to see the changes that will be made.
So let's clean this up.
I have too many chips open, so terraformed plane and just kind of close to this.
And let's see, so some are here, one resource will be destroyed, one resource will be added, and
that scroll up and you see that the change that we just made, which is adding this user data execution
here, actually forces the previous server or previous U.S. to instance, this one to be destroyed and
you one to be created.
So this is a change that will recreate the whole instance, which is fine for us.
So we are going to just apply.
So while this is applying, note that this blog here will only get executed once, right?
So, for example, if we make changes to the text, which will be basically just modifying existing
server, like we just add another key player here, something else, and the whole thing gets executed.
This will only be executed once right on initial run.
So just keep that in mind.
So let's go back and you see that server, the previous one is getting destroyed.
And let's wait a couple of seconds until the new one comes up.
And this time we actually added output SC to public IP.
So we should see that in output here instead of going to the management console to get the public IP
address of the new AC2 instance, it will just save us some time.
And there you go, as you see, the new public IP address is printed out here and now if we grab this
public IP address and S.H. into the server and now hopefully all of these comments should have executed.
And if we do, yes, there you go.
We see our Ingenix container already up and running and the port building is already in place.
Now, we already configured security group for that.
So Port 80 80 should be accessible from Browsr as well.
So that means that on this public IP address.
Import 80 80, we should see engineers welcome page.
So everything is working, our setup is done.
So this is a very simple but realistic configuration of creating a new PC with all the different configurations
connecting to Internet, configuring the firewall rules, deploying easy to instance, and also running
some entry point scripts so that docker gets installed and docker container starts running on it.
Now, of course, if you have a much longer and maybe more complicated script that you want to execute
as an entry point script, when the server starts, maybe you installing a couple of different tools
and configuring lots of different stuff, you can also reference it from a file instead of having it
inside the terraformed configuration file.
Right.
So I'm just going to.
Do it this or copy this, and just like we did right here, we can very simply reference a file here
and we can pass in the file location.
And let's say this is an entry entry script.
That is H.
So this is going to be a shell script that TerraForm will execute on the server.
And this is actually a location or relative path.
So we can create a file called into script entry script to S.H. inside our terraformed folder.
So I'm going to do an entry script that is H and I'm going to paste in what I copied.
And obviously we don't need this block here.
It was just, um, to have a multiline string right here in TerraForm.
This is just a very normal shell script and this will work as well.
So if I save it and do terraform PLEN.
And let's actually see.
The terraformed action, as you see this change also will cause is it, for instance, to be recreated
or a new one to be created?
Let's actually go ahead and do that.
And let's actually check out the new public IP address real quick to make sure it is working.
And there you go.
We get the same welcome to engineers speech.
So this is actually cleaner because we're separating the Shell script from terraformed configuration
file by just referencing the file instead of having the whole script inside the configuration file in
here.
So, as I said, we can write a bunch of more stuff in here that installs, configures, deployers applications
and stuff on the server.
And now is a final step, we can actually check all this code into a separate feature branch and push
it to the remote repository so we can do it, check out and we're going to create a new branch and let's
call it feature deploy, too easy to do with different components.
And now we have all the changes that we made in the master branch transferred to this new branch.
And here we can just add everything and commit the new configuration.
And finally, we can just push the whole branch to a remote repository.