Now, there is an important point to be made here, because we just created infrastructure or configure
the networking around the server and then provisioned a server, is it, for instance, in that network
configuration, all using terraform?
Right.
And then once the infrastructure is actually ready and it's time to deploy applications and install
stuff on it, we actually switched back to Shell script.
Right?
We just executing very normal commands which have nothing to do with TerraForm.
So the point here is that once the server is created, once the infrastructure is there, TerraForm
doesn't help further with installing the tools or in this case, installing Docker and configuring our
server any further.
It gives us the possibility to execute a script by giving the attribute.
But we can't debug, for example.
Right?
So if something goes wrong here in this command execution, we won't get a message or we won't get a
feedback.
We will still have to S.H. into it and we will have to see what happened, why doesn't work, et cetera.
And also, you need to know shell scripting.
Right.
So this is basically terraformed syntax, but you still have to know how to write shell scripts and
how to execute shell commands.
So there is no terraform command or config on a higher level.
Right.
So we still have to work with lower level commands.
We don't have something like install Docker on easy to resource, for example, or start Ingenix container
with these parameters resource.
And that's where it's important to know what Terraformed should be used for and where terraform usage
or use case actually stops.
And I think this is a perfect example that makes it clear that terraform is a tool for creating, configuring
and managing infrastructure.
So the underlying hardware like networking configuration, the server creating the key here, etc. But
once the servers are provisioned, the firewall rules are sets, et cetera, deploying the application
or configuring the server itself, installing packages or updating their versions and so on should be
done with another tool.
This is where TerraForm doesn't help us that much, right?
It gives us these ways of doing it, but it's not actually made for these use cases.
So the question is, what are alternatives or do you have to use shell scripting and you have to know
how to write shell scripts?
And there are actually other infrastructure as code tools.
They're specifically made for deploying applications and configuring existing servers.
So once the infrastructure is provisioned with a tool like TerraForm, for example, then tools like
Ansible Puppet or chef, which are configuration management tools, come in to automate deploying the
application, configuring the server, installing different packages, updating the versions of applications
and so on.
And this is also something that terraformed documentation.
States that terraform should be used for provisioning infrastructure.
And if you want to then automate the further steps of deploying applications on that provision infrastructure,
then you should do that with tools like Ansible, which is one of the most popular configuration tools
out there for such use cases.
So as you see, in an ideal case, we have lots of infrastructure provision and maybe you have very
complex application configuration on the provision infrastructure then in these type of projects.
Actually, it's very common that people use TerraForm and then Ansible together to cover or to automate
these two parts or two levels of configuration on infrastructure and then application level.
And as I said, this example makes it very clear.