So now that we understand some of the basics of TerraForm and how to use its configuration file and
the basic syntax of terraform to create resources, fetch data, create variables and so on, let's
actually now see some realistic use case with TerraForm in NYC.
So what we're going to do is we're going to deploy and you see two instance of virtual server on each
of us and we're going to run a simple docker container on it.
However, in order to create that instance, we're going to create the whole infrastructure on us.
So first, we're going to need and own VPC.
So we're going to create our own VPC instead of using the default one from the region inside our APC,
we're going to create one subnet in one of the availability zones.
Know that we can create multiple subnets in each AC.
In our case, we're just going to create one subnet in one of the pieces, right.
Because we just want a simple use case with one server and we're going to connect this VPC to Internet
using Internet gateway on enable us.
So basically we want to allow traffic to and from VPC with Internet.
Right.
So outside of VPC, we want to be able to connect to our Isleta server inside VPC or resources, and
we want requests to go out to Internet.
And then in this configured VPC, inside the subnet that we create, we're going to deploy our AC to
instance, and this is a two instance, will basically run a very simple docker container.
We're going to deploy Ingenix Docker container on it.
And because we want to simulate kind of Web application deployment on institue server, we're going
to want to access it from the browser.
Right.
And that means that we're going to need to open firewall rules in order to access the Ingenix server
running on the SC, too.
And we also want to S.H. into our server.
And that means we're going to open the SSA each port on the server as well.
And for that, we're going to create a security group with those two ports configured.
Right.
So we're going to open up these ports through security group.
So we're going to do all of this one by one.
Now, it may sound like we're doing a lot because we're creating a lot of components to deploy a simple
server inside.
However, when you have a multi server deployment, basically you just have to create this whole network
and infrastructure configuration once.
So you basically have just one VPC, maybe multiple subnets, and you just deploy all the servers inside.
And generally, when working with a command line interface or even management console, you can create
the easy two instances in the default be PC that comes out of the box with every region.
Right.
So you don't have to create a new PC and a new subnet to launch your Ishita instance there.
However, in TerraForm, it is a best practice to create new resources rather than use the default components
that AWB provides us with.
So that also when we clean up all the resources, basically we can remove the components that we created
because we can remove the default VPC component from Adewusi.
So that means that we want to create our own.
We obviously want to work with our own VPC and leave the default one.
Basically, as is, we're not going to make any changes inside.
So with that overview, let's actually get started.