So the first step, as I said, is creating our own VPC and then creating a subnet inside that PC in
one of the availability zones of the region and then exposing the VPC to Internet or connecting it to
the Internet using Internet gateway.
So let's do and prepare all of this first before creating the easy to let's actually clean this up a
little bit so that we are starting from a clean state.
First of all, I'm going to remove all the validation and stuff from the variables.
And right now we have Seiter blogs and Avildsen on variables and we have the BBC and subnet configuration
from the previous part.
And let's actually make some changes to this to make it more reusable and clean up a little.
I have renamed the VPC and Subnet to be my FBC and my subnet to be independent of the environment because
let's say we are passing in the environment whether it's develop or staging or production from outside.
So all of this is more or less generic and let's actually make this Seiter Block's own variables.
So let's create a variable called VPC sided look and another one for subnet Seiter block.
And these are going to be separate variables and we're going to assign values to those variables at
the end.
So we have the site or blog here and subnet block.
Right.
So this to change and then we have the availability zone is a variable also set and we can decide in
which aisi of the region the summit will be created and the easy to land will be deployed in.
And let's also change the name tag.
So for every component that we're creating, let's give it a prefix of the environment that it's going
to be deployed.
And so on a development server, all components will have dev prefix on production environment that
will have proper prefix and so on.
So I'm going to create a variable called let's call it in prefix and I'm leaving all the variables empty
later.
We can do validation here, we can do type shak description, et cetera.
Right now they're pretty descriptive from the naming, so let's leave it empty.
And what we're going to do is we're going to do string interpolation that's basically having variable
value and string glued together.
Right.
So we're going to do something like a devil VPC.
And this Dev will be basically a prefix that is set as a variable.
In order to use the variable value, we're going to do dollar sign and curly braces.
Right.
So using variable outside, not inside the string or inside the quotes is var variable name.
If we want to use the variable inside a string because we want to glue it or put it together with another
string, we are using sine curly braces and inside here we can do var and the variable name.
So this is how we can use variables inside the strings and we're going to do the same for all the other
components.
So let's do prefix first.
So this is going to be Dev or Prad or sieging whatever Desh subnet one.
Great.
So we have VPC and we have the subnet.
No, let's actually create these two again and we're going to see some of the components that AWB creates
by default whenever we create a new VPC.
So I'm going to save this.
Let's actually assign values to those variables.
So I have deleted my terraformed or Tebartz content, so it's completely empty.
We're going to now start setting those values.
So I'm just going to copy all of them.
Let's remove the variable here and just leave the names and we're going to assign values to each.
So first of all, VPC, let's give it the same one as before.
It's going to be 10 zero zero zero 16 and.
Let's make it 10 zero 10, zero 24.
Let's have the availabilities on to you W three B and let's make the environment prefix def so we have
all the values we need.
We can also said the region in the provider is an alternative to setting it as an environmental variable
in the command line interface before executing TerraForm.
I'm just going to set it here and this is going to be U w three.
That's the region and we're creating the subnet in one of these regions, Azeez.
So everything is ready for the simple use case, which we have actually already executed before.
And first of all, let's do terraform PLEN.
This will show us what TerraForm will be executing.
And since I have deleted everything created previously, right now I see that subnet will be created
in VPC as well.
So let's actually apply this.
I'm going to do auto proof so that I don't need to input confirmation for appli.
And let's see.
Great.
So two resources have been added.
Let's now go to, you know, use console and let's go to VPC.
And.
Here I have.
The Devil VPC, this is the name that we provided here, this was the environmental prefix set here,
DEVE and VPC, so this is the default one that every region comes with.
This is what IWC generates for every region by default.
And this is the second one that we just created, and this is the seiter block we specified.
And let's also check the subnets.
And again, I have three default summits because by default a default risk comes with default subnets,
one per availability zone in that region.
So if a region has three zones, then it's going to have three subnets.
And this is ours.
And it's good to give names to our components because that we can differentiate it from the default
ones.
And we know that it's the one that we created.
So our summit is here as well.
Let's actually go inside the VPC and let's see some of the things that Adewusi actually generated for
us once we created this VPC.