So I'm going to click inside and this is our VPC detail of you, and here you see some of the different
components.
First of all, a round table was generated by us for our newly created VPC.
So round table again is like a virtual router in your private network, right?
So in the VPC, in virtual private cloud, basically we get our private network right and we have these
IP range available inside that network.
And we have a round table.
Right.
And round table basically decides where the traffic will be forwarded to within the VPC.
So it actually gives us a round table by default whenever we create a VPC because we didn't specify
it here.
Right.
We didn't explicitly create a round table.
It was just generated because every VPC needs one.
And we also have a network ACL, which is basically a firewall configuration for our VPC, which applies
to subnets in that VPC.
Right.
So this is a difficult one.
Let's actually check it out.
And just like the security group, which is firewall configuration for servers.
So on a server level, this is on some level and it also has inbound and outbound rules and by default,
everything is open.
So basically network ACL doesn't actually restrict any traffic.
It is open by default.
Security groups are closed by default.
And of course, we can configure this as we wish.
So let's go back to VPC again and let's click Inside Row Table.
I'm going to make it bigger.
So inside the row table, this is the one we have to actually remove this filter.
You see that we have two tables because one is of the default VPC.
It comes with its own row table and this is one for our newly created VPC.
Right.
And these are the main row tables or the default ones.
So this one is ours.
This is our VPC, Edem.
And if I click in Roads.
Here you see one road configured, as I said, round table, basically roads, the traffic within a
VPC.
So, for example, if we have multiple you see two instances inside the VPC or some other resources
inside, basically what table will be handling and managing the traffic between them.
And as you see here, we have one entry and we have a destination, these IP addresses from the range.
So this is a range of IP addresses.
And if you remember, this is actually the same range we specified for our VPC right here.
If we go to variables, this is the same exact site, a blog in our VPC.
We have a round table that basically handles all the traffic inside our VPC and we know it's a traffic
inside of because the IP address range matches our vehicles.
IP address range and local target basically means that this is handled within the VPC.
It doesn't go outside to the Internet, it stays within our virtual private cloud and our private network.
Right.
So that is the entry that we have by default.
And that means that our VPC isn't connected to Internet.
All the traffic right now is handled within the VPC, but nothing goes outside or comes inside.
And if I actually click inside the round table of the default VPC of the region here, I have two entries.
The one is similar to this one.
Which is basically the IP address range of that VPC.
Right.
This is the default BBC IP range.
It has local targets, so basically traffic within and we have the second entry, which basically covers
all the IP addresses of the world, each and every one of them, and is a target.
We have Internet gateway.
So this means that this round table actually handles or will handle all the traffic coming from the
Internet and living the Internet.
Right.
So these Internet gateway is configured for the VPC, for Internet connectivity.
And you can see some other details about the Internet gateway.
However, this is all we need to know at the moment.
So basically.
That means that we need the same entry right here so that we can connect our VPC to the Internet and
we're going to create there also with TerraForm.
So let's go back to our main T.F. And, you know, next line, we're actually going to create a new
round table.
So what we're going to do is we're going to create a new round table.
We're not going to use the default one.
We're going to create a new round table and we're going to create those two rules.
So basically the one for internal traffic and one for connected to Internet.
So let's go back to our main terraform file and let's define a resource called A.W. as
Round Table.
And let's actually call it my AMPE.
Rhodes table for consistency, and inside here, we're going to configure some attributes, so first
of all, we need to decide which VPC this round table will belong to.
We're creating this round table in our VPC, obviously, so we're going to reference it.
Like this.
Is a second attribute we are going to have to define the rot's.
So each road will be its own block, these are basically the entries right here now by default, the
entry for the VPC, internal routing is configured automatically, right.
So that means that this first entry for the new round table that we're creating.
Not this one.
Not the default one.
This entry will be automatically created, so we don't have to specifically define it or we can't actually
define it at all, so we're going to leave that out.
So instead, we're going to have to create the second entry, which basically handles the Internet gateway.
And this is going to be the roadblock for that.
And look, we have two attributes.
We have Seiter block, and this is going to be basically any IP address which is represented by zeros.
And the second attribute is Gateway.
And this is going to be the Internet gateway idea for our table now for our VPC.
Actually, we don't have an Internet gateway, so we are going to need to create that resource and.
It's actually pretty easy.
Resource.
Adewusi Internet Gateway, and again, let's call it my Internet gateway, and here we have
just one attribute that we need to define, which is the PC, right.
So we are creating Internet Gateway in the BBC and then we are using that Internet gateway inside our
roundtable to tell the roundtable, hey, please handle the requests of the BBC to go to and also come
in from the Internet.
So we're going to reference this Internet gateway here, you know, round table.
Like this and Edem, because we're going to need it, right, and finally, we're going to add some
texture, we want to take each component so that we know it is created by us and also that it belongs
to the same environment.
Let's use the same prefix.
And let's call it let's call it real Tibble.
Like this, and let's use the same take for the Internet gateway.
Right.
And by the way, even though this resource needs to be created first so that raw table can reference
it, it doesn't have to be defined before the resource.
So basically in terraformed, this is a good thing.
That terraform is smart enough to figure out in which order or in which sequence it needs to create
the resources.
So, for example, if you have one resource referenced in another, one terraform can figure out that
the first resource needs to be created first.
So even if we define it in the, let's say, wrong order, TerraForm will figure out which resource
to create first and so on.
So we don't have to define it in any particular order, which is a good thing about terraform.
It can figure out these kind of dependencies.
So let's leave it like this.
So if you look again at our configuration, we have the VPC subnet inside.
We're connecting VPC to Internet Gateway and then we are configuring a new round table that we're creating
in the VPC to routes all the traffic to and from Internet using this Internet gateway.
So think about the round table is a virtual router inside your VPC and you can think about Internet
Gateway as a virtual modem that connects you to the Internet and with this configuration.
Let's actually do terraform plan and let's see what will happen when we apply this.
And there you go.
The BBC and some that are already created, so this time the Internet gateway and roundtable table will
be created.
So let's actually apply.
And let's check.
I'm going to refresh this, and there you go.
We have a round table that we just created and as you see right here, it says not main raw table.
So basically, this is like a default round table for our VPC and this is the secondary or not default.
So we have created a new round table.
And if we scroll to the results.
We have the same entry as before.
So this is our VPC IP address range, and as I said, we didn't specify this in our configuration,
this was created by default without having to specify it.
So we have that right here.
And this is the one that we configured.
We have a routing to and from all the IP addresses using Internet gateway.
And this is the Internet gateway that we created.
This one right here, it has the tank and it belongs to our VPC.
So now our VPC is configured to allow Internet traffic.