Now, there's one more thing we need to configure with our round table, and that is if I actually click
in this one, for example, we have a tab called subnet associations.
And basically this means that we have created a round table inside our VPC.
However, we need to associate subnets with the round table so the traffic within the subnet can also
be handled by the round table.
So if I click inside here, you see that there is no association defined here.
However, we have a note that by default, when you do not associate subnets to a round table, they're
automatically assigned or associated to the main road table.
Of course, in that VPC where the subnet is running.
So the main row table is basically the one that says yes in the main column.
So this is the default row table.
This is not ours.
This is from the default VPC.
And this is actually our two round tables in our boxes, and this is the main one.
However, we want the subnet to be associated with the table that we created because this is the one
that has Internet gateway configured and we want our subnet to be connected to the Internet gateway
as well.
Right.
So right now, subnet is associated with the main or this round table that doesn't have Internet gateway
here.
So let's actually change that.
And we're going to do that also in TerraForm.
It's a very straightforward and simple resource.
It's called A.W. s Round Table Association.
And let's actually call it association round table subnet maybe.
And we just have two parameters, which is the subnet, Edem.
Which we can grab right here from the subnets resource and also don't forget, we always have to use
the ID and the attribute of that object.
And the second attribute, which is the round table, is pretty straightforward.
We're associating this, too.
So we just need IDs of the both and row table ID we can grab here.
My table and also don't forget, I did a tribute, so let's play that.
And one resource God created and if I refresh the page, no.
And go to some associations, you see that now we have an explicit summit association with our roundtable,
so our summit or all the resources, including Ishita that we're going to deploy into our summit will
be or all of these requests will be handled by this roundtable.
So we can SFH into the issue, for instance, as well as Access Ingenix Web server through the browser.
So all of that is configured.