Now, you may be wondering, what if we used the default row table instead of creating a new one, because
we already have one that we get out of the box for our VPC, right.
Generated by us.
So why can't we just add a new routes to the defaults row table instead of creating a new one?
And there is an option if you want to use the default round table.
And I'm going to show you how to do that as well.
So let's go back to our.
Terraformed config, and let's actually remove this one here, the association, as well as remove the
roots table resource or let's actually comment this out to see the difference.
So first, I'm going to apply this and the round table and association with some that will be removed
and then we'll just edit the default rule table.
So I'm going to refresh this again, and there you go.
We have one row table default one, and that's it.
However, we still have our Internet gateway and we're going to associate this or we're going to configure
this in the default row table.
So we're going to make a second entry in this rot's.
And the way we can configure the default row table is using a resource called Innovest Default.
Round table and again, all of these components of this resource types, you can look them up in the
documentation and let's call it a default round table, or we can also call it main table.
And there are a couple of attributes we need here.
So in the new round table that we defined, we had VPC, ID configures.
However, here we don't need a VPC ID because we're referencing an existing round table.
Right.
So instead we have default.
Round table, I did.
So we need the idea of that round table and we can get that idea actually from the VPC object.
And the way we can do that is actually let's clear this up.
And using terraformed state show command, we can actually reference the BPC object.
So if I do terraformed stage show and the resource name, I can see all the attributes that this resource
has.
However, I need to have that resource existing in my account, otherwise I won't be able to get any
list.
But since the VPC exist, I get the list of all its attributes.
And one of them is, you see here is default row table ID.
So that's how I know how to access the round table Edem in my VPC.
So I'm going to copy that and A.W. as VPC type.
That's actually copy this and copy that again.
And there you go.
So this is our Rapke object and we're referencing an existing round table idea of the main round table
like this.
So we don't have to know the ID value, actually.
So that's the first attribute and actually the only attribute that is different from creating a new
round table.
The rest of the stuff are actually the same.
So again, we are adding a new road, just like we did with the previous one.
The default one is already there.
So we don't have to specify or change or do anything about it.
And we can also give it a tick.
We can actually call it the main or TB.
And I'm going to save this and let's actually plan first and see the preview of this.
Let's see, we have default round table is a new resource.
And let's do a play.
And let's actually refresh.
So, as you see, what happened is that the previous round table got removed and the new one got created
in its place, which is also a main one.
That's why we saw the create and not modify or change.
And if we scroll in the road section here, you see the default local routing and gateway configuration
right here.
And we have the name tags as well.
And we're using the main road table.
And in some associations, we haven't defined any explicit subnet association for this round table.
However, subnets in that we see all the summits that are not explicitly associated are automatically
assigned to the main road table, which happens to be this one.
So we don't have to explicitly do the association again because it will happen by default.
So this is basically how you can use the default resource, in this case a default round table instead
of creating a new one.
And now we can actually remove.
This block of code here.