Now is a next step, we're going to configure federal rules for our Ishita instance, so when we deploy
our virtual machine in the subnet, we want to be able to S.H. into it.
So we want to open Port 22 as well as we want to be accessing the Ingenix Web server that we deploy
as a container through the Web browser.
So we want to open port irritating so that we can access from the Web browser.
So we're going to create a security group and open those two ports on our server.
And in order to create a security group, we can use resource type Adewusi Security
Group and let's call it my EP is G, and we're going to have a bunch of attributes in here.
First of all, we have the name, which we can call it the same, I assume then we have the VPC ID,
so we have to associate the security group with the VPC so that the servers inside that VPC can be associated
with the security group and VPC Edem.
We're going to get, as always from referencing our VPC and this is the main or the interesting part
where we define the rules, the federal rules of the security group.
So generally, we have two types of rules, right?
We have traffic that is coming inside the VPC and entering the servers.
So the incoming traffic, for example, when we S.H. into the server, when we exit from the browser,
we're basically sending traffic inside the VPC into our easy to instant's right into our server.
And the incoming traffic or incoming traffic rules are configured using an attribute called ingress.
So ingress for incoming and inside ingress block.
We have configuration for one firewall rule and we have a couple of attributes here.
First of all, we have from port and for SSA each port for 22, we're going to define it to be twenty
two and then we have to port and we're going to also say to twenty two.
So why do we have two ports from.
And two is because we can actually configure a range.
Right now we're just setting it to one specific port, but we can also configure a range of ports to
open in a security group.
So if you want, for example, to open ports from zero to 1000 on a single server, then we can have
a range instead of one specific port.
In our case, we just need Port 22.
So let's leave it at that.
And then we have the protocol, which is just simple TCP and then we have the source.
So basically who is allowed or which IP addresses are allowed to access port or port range defined here?
And this is going to be seiter block.
So this is an IP address range or a list of IP addresses or site blocks that are allowed to access port
defined in here, and for SSA, as you know, accessing a server on S.H. should be secure and not everyone
should be allowed to do it.
So you can have a handful of IP addresses that are permitted to do that.
For example, if you have a team of three developers, engineers who are all accessing or SSA into that
server, you can define their IP addresses as at least here in your case, we just have one, which
is our local machine.
So we're going to define here our own IP address and you can actually check that out very easily using
a website or also just checking in your operating system and set it as a value here.
But remember, this is not an IP address.
It's a site or blog.
Right.
So you are defining a range of IP addresses.
And since we just want one single IP address, not a range, we are going to fixated at 32.
So this will map to this specific IP address.
Now, if your IP address is dynamic, so if this actually changes a lot, you can configure it as a
variable and exit or reference it from the variable value instead of hard coding it here.
Or you can also have the whole list as a variable if you have a list of IP addresses that are also dynamic.
But again, because we have just one, I'm going to extract this value here and I'm going to access
it from a variable and let's actually call it my IP so that I don't forget to declare and assign this
value.
I'm going to immediately define it here, my IP, and let's also set it as a value in here.
And there you go.
So if this value changes, basically, I can simply change it here instead of going through the configuration
file and scrolling through to see where I set it.
And also, I don't have to check this into the repository because this is the local variables file that
we ignored, as you remember, in the get ignore.
We just excluded it from being checked in because everyone can have their own copy of Variables File
and set their own IP address, as well as other variable values here and have a local copy of the variables.
So that basically configures one incoming rule for Port is S.H..
Now we need a second one for Port Eighty and I'm just going to copy this one and we're going to set
the port to eighty eighty.
It's going to be TCP protocol and here we don't want to restrict it to any IP address because anyone
can access it from the browser.
So we're going to set.
Sadr block to be any IP address that can access the server on Port 80 80, and this basically takes
care of the incoming traffic rules.
But we also have the outgoing traffic rules and the exiting traffic can be configured using an attribute
called egress.
So ingress for incoming egress for exiting.
And the attributes for this are actually the same.
The values are, however, different because we don't want to restrict the existing traffic to the Internet
from the server and examples of traffic that is leaving the server or leaving the BPC.
Our private network is basically when you have to install something on the server.
For example, when we install Docker or some other tools on our server, these binaries need to be fetched
from Internet, right.
Or when we installed some Linux packages, they have to be fetched and downloaded on the server from
Internet.
Or for example, when we started Docker Container of Ingenix Image, for example, the Ingenix image
has to be fetched from Docker Hub.
Right.
So this means that the request is going outside to the Internet in order to fetch some resource.
And of course, we want to allow that request to be able to leave the VPC and go get something from
Internet.
But we don't want to restrict it on any port IP address.
So we're going to send it to any port by sending this to zero.
And we also don't want to restrict the protocol.
We just going to configure for any and any IP address, as well as just an empty prefix list.
It is.
It's just for allowing access to VPC endpoints.
It's not very interesting for us.
This will just allow any traffic to leave the PC and the server itself, and this will configure all
the rules in our security group.
And finally, we can have the name tag that's actually just copied from here and let's call it security
group, S.G. and that's it.
So now we can apply this configuration and create a new security group inside our VPC.
So first, let's do terraform plan.
And terraformed plan actually shows us an error on each line, and this is actually one very good feature
of terraformed, that it has an inbuilt validation, right.
So if I make some syntax error, if the attribute name isn't defined correctly or maybe I am referencing
a variable that hasn't been declared or if something is wrong, basically terraformed validates this
input and tells me exactly on which line, what error I have.
So in this case, I apparently forgot the S or the plural inside or blocks.
So let's go back to configuration file.
I have to specify Seiter blocks instead of Cita Block because it is a list, so let's save it and I'm
going to do plen again.
And.
This time, the file is valid and I see that security group will be created with all this configuration
so we can actually apply this.
And it got executed, so now in the VPC section, let's actually find security groups, it's right here.
And as I see, we have three security groups here.
One of them belongs to our default VPC of the region.
The second one is the default security group of the VPC that we created.
Right.
So remember, I said that we create some default components for VPC whenever we create one security
group is one of them.
So whenever we create a new VPC, a default security group gets created for that specific VPC with default
configuration and by default, security group is blocked.
So all the ports are basically closed, so no traffic is allowed in.
So this is the default security group of our VPC and this is the security group we just created.
And this is the name that we defined here.
We have the name for the security group name column and then we have the name tag, which is what we
define in the text.
And now let's actually check the Enron rules for that, and there you go.
We have the Secich type Port 20 to my IP address and we have TCP IP custom DP for Port, AT&amp;T from all
the sources.
And outbound rule is what we configured here.
And this basically maps to this entry, which basically says all traffic allowed, all protocols allowed,
all port ranges for all IP addresses.
This is what we configured with these attributes here.
So security group is created.
It is correctly configured and ready to be used and assigned to InSitu instance that we're going to
deploy.
Now, again, you may be wondering what if we wanted to use the existing default security group because
it comes out of the box when we create a new book.
So can we reuse it?
And the answer is yes, we can reuse the default one.
We don't have to create a new one.
And I'm going to show you the syntax for configuring default security group instead of creating a new
one.
So let's go back to our configuration, and it's actually very easy to switch from creating a new security
group to default on a security group.
So in the research definition right here, we're going to define a default security group, resource
type.
So since there is just one default security group or default rule table in a VPC terraform and everybody
will know which specific security group that is, and we can also call it default security group.
And as you saw, the name of the security group name is also default.
We can actually remove it and the rest of the configuration is actually exactly the same.
We have the BBC ID ingress rules, egress rules and the tag.
We can actually default in here and call it debt default security group.
And let's now execute TerraForm PLEN.
And see our changes.
And as you see.
One resource will be created and one will be destroyed.
So basically we have removed one resource from the configuration file and we are defining a default
security group, a new resource.
So let's do terraform, applied or approve.
And let us check this out, going to refresh and there you go.
And if I click inside and see the outbound rules are basically allowing any traffic and inbound rules
we have.
Our custom Tsipi and as a Sage Por 22, the group name is Default, as it was previously, and we have
the tech name here.
So that's how we can adjust an existing default security group or basically just recreate or replace
it instead of creating a new known default security group in the VPC.