Great, so let's review we have a BBC that has a subnet inside, we have connected the BBC to Internet
using the Internet gateway and configured it in the round table.
And we have also created a security group that opens Port 22 in Port 80 that we will later configure
for our Ishita instance.
Now, the question is, what else or what other configuration or what other information do we actually
need in order to create an ISA to instant's?
So I'm going to write the configuration for creating and it was easy to instance and let's see what
information are is still missing.
So first of all, the resource in this instance is the resource type and let's call it my Web server.
And there are two required attributes, for instance, the first required attribute is, am I Aimi is
the image which the easy server will be based on.
This is the operating system image.
Right.
So if we go back to our console and let's look for AC2 and by the way, this is actually a new user
interface of us, maybe experimental, actually.
So right now there are no running instances.
So here, if we launch instance, the very first selection we have to make is to choose an Amazon machine
image.
And as I said, this is the operating system that the server will start with so we can choose between
distributions of Linux and Windows and the image that we're going to use for our Web server is Amazon
Linux, which is optimized for working with Amazon and its services.
So this is also the one that we're going to use in this one.
So the Aimi the value of this Aimi attribute is actually the idea of the image.
So basically this part right here.
Right.
So each Aimi has this ID, which starts with my dash, and then comes the ID and each one has a unique
one.
And this is the value that we need.
Now, note that this ID can actually be different across regions.
So in your region, the ID might be actually different for the same image, for the same machine image.
So keep that in mind.
And also this can be dynamic.
So this can actually change when the new image gets released.
And that means that if we hardcoded this value for copy this and basically just hardcoded as a string
here, we may need to change it later when the idea isn't correct anymore.
So instead, we actually want to dynamically set it or rather get this value from Adewusi programmatically
from TerraForm and then set it as a value here.
So how do we do that?
You know that in order to fetch the existing resources to basically query the data from us, we use
not resource, but rather data type.
Right.
So what we're going to do is we're going to create a data and we're going to call it a.
And we want this image to be the latest Amazon links to image.
So this one right here, but with the latest version.
So let's call the latest Amazon Linux.
Image, so instead of hard coating it here, we're going to clear it from us.
So first attribute is going to be most recent.
Equals true.
We want to get the most recent image version, the second one will be Bonar's.
So what is the owners value for an image?
Let's go back.
And here you see, this is just a quick start, but you have different takes.
You're right.
You have in a marketplace where different companies have created their own images.
Right.
So you can actually browse these ones and then you have owner is basically the one that released this
image or who makes this image available in the marketplace.
Then you have community images, which are four different operating systems with different distributions.
A whole list here.
And I'm actually going to open a new tab.
And let's go to E2 and in InSitu view here, you have images and images in this menu here and if we
click inside.
And that's the public images.
We have loads of them, right, and the way to search or see the owner is basically in this owner field
and for example, if I input's this ID here and search for it.
There you go.
We have owner fields that says Amazon, and because this is the image that I want to be using, this
is basically the same one is here.
This is the name and this is it.
So this tells me the owner of the image.
So this is the value that I want to enter in here.
And this is a lease so I can have multiple owners specified here.
I can also have my own images right again if I go back.
You have my in my section here, for example, if you create an easy two instance from this image and
then you make changes on top of that, like install some tools, etc., and just prepared for your own
needs, you can actually create your own image out of it and then reuse that for other deployments.
And then you're going to have them in this section and you can reference them here as well.
In this case, you will be the owner.
So we have the owners, which is Amazon, and then we have the filters.
So filter in data, basically filter blocks are what lets you define the criteria for these queries.
So basically you can tell Amazon, give me the most recent images that are owned by Amazon that have
the name that starts with this string, for example, or we can say that starts with this string or
this value and that ends with this.
And we don't care whatever is inside in case there are multiple images like that and we don't care which
one will be taken.
In fact, I'm going to choose Amazon Linux here.
And you see that we have two images that have the same prefix, same suffix.
Just the in between is different, right?
This value here is different.
So we can actually do that in filter.
So I'm going to copy that part.
And in filter we have name and values attributes for each filter.
We have the name attribute which basically is referencing which key we want to filter on in our case.
This is the name of the image.
So we want to filter or set criteria for name.
So we're going to specify a name.
In this case.
It's called the same.
Not to be confused.
And we have the values, so for this attribute or this column, basically what values we want to filter
out.
And as I said, we want the value to be this is a least so we can have multiple values.
And we want that to start with this string right here.
And then we want something in between.
We don't really care.
It's a regular expression for that.
And then we want it to end with this string.
And this will basically give us all the images that match images whose name matches this regular expression,
in this case, it will be those two.
And then give me the most recent of those images and we can actually define as many filters as we want.
In fact, we can do the second one.
And again, we have a name for the attribute we want to filter on.
Let's go back and let's say we want the virtualization type to be filtering on this time.
I'm going to copy that, actually.
And attributes is going to be like this.
So name virtualization type and values.
Again, we have a list and the value is each VM.
So I have another criteria, and this way you can add many multiple filters from whatever data you are
querying from us, and this will be this will basically give us the most recent Amazon image that matches
this name.
And this way, we don't have to worry about hard coding and updating the value manually.
It will be dynamically provided for us.
So now we can reference that Aimi from the data using data, the name of the data thoughts or the type
of the data in the name of the data.
However, again, this gives us the whole object, the whole image with all the attributes and we just
want the I.D. So we're going to access the ID attribute and set it to Aimi.
And before we do that, let's actually output the results of this query so that we can test whether
our filter criteria are set correctly and so on.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to do output and let's call it and the value or database in my
ID and value is going to be.
This one right here.
Or we can also uproot the whole object, actually, so I'm going to do terraformed plan first.
And tearful PLEN will actually give us.
The Output's objects with all the attributes or the values that we get from each of us.
So in this case, terraform actually fetch the data and we see the results here without executing the
appli.
So we see the whole Aimi object attributes here.
So we see a bunch of attributes like creation, date, description.
And this actually matches the description right here.
These are filters and we have the ID as well as image I.D., which is the same value, have the image
location owner.
Name as we filtered, basically, and so on, so we have a bunch of those here, but we're just interested
in it.
However, with output is how you can actually validate what result you're getting with this data execution.
So I'm going to add it here.
And let's do terraformed planet again.
And this time I get just the idea, and this is actually with 039, the idea right here, so we're actually
getting the correct Aimi back from us.
This is the one here.
Great.
So we that configured.
Let's come in the scene again, so we have the first required attribute, which is.