The second required attribute is instance type, and this is is, you know, basically just the type
of the server defined right here.
So based on how much resources you want, you can choose all of the types if you want the free tier
eligible one.
Let's go with T two micro.
And instead of hard coding the type here, maybe you want to deploy different types in different environments.
We can also make this configurable and actually reference it as a variable.
So let's create instance type variable.
Let's define it up here
and let's assign its value right away and set it to T to T to micro.
It's this value right here.
So we have the two required attributes set.
Now the rest are optional.
However, we want to set some of the configuration so that our easy to instant's actually ends up in
the subnet.
That we created in the BBC and gets the.
Security group that we defined right here now, as I said, these attributes or the rest of the attributes
are optional, like subnet ID and security group I.D., et cetera.
And it means that if we do not specify them explicitly, then the ISATOU instance that we define here
will actually be launched in a default VPC in one of the azeez in that region.
In one of the subnets, however, we have created our own VPC and we want this easy to to end up in
our VPC, in the subnet that we created and be assigned the security group that we created in our VPC.
Right.
So because we don't want the instance to be launched in the default VPC, but rather in ours, we have
to specify all these values.
Right.
So optional just means that the default components will be used.
However, we want to override that.
So let's specify some of these values.
First, we have the subnet ID and we want our InSitu to end up in our subnet again.
If we had multiple of them, we could.
Choose whichever one.
We just have one, so that's easy to choose from, and that's our summit.
It is the next one.
We have VPC security group.
It is.
And this is actually a list because we can assign and configure multiple security groups for our AC2
instance, not just one.
We just have one.
So I'm going to reference that it's a serious default security group.
Default is cheap, and I almost forgot.
We need to use the I.D. and not the whole object.
Otherwise, Terraformed will give us a warning when we execute terraformed plan.
So we have the Senate ID and we have the security group I.D. and now we can said the event is on.
And you remember that we have actually configured the availability zone as a variable and we used it
in subnet as well.
So we can just grab that variable and use it here as well.
And this will basically tell terraformed to spin up the server in the subnet and assign it the security
group we defined for it.
And since the subnet is also in this specific AC.
This will basically do the same in other attribute to set is associate public IP address because we
want to be able to access this from browser and as well as research into it.
So we need a public IP address of the server.
So associated public IP address will be true.
And one final thing again, for ECES, reaching into the server is the keys.
And if I go back to the U.S. to actually leave this wizard, we don't want this anymore.
Let's go to Isatou.
And in this overview, you see key players and these are basically this is empty right now.
But these are the key players that allow you to S.H. into the server by creating public private keep
here or SFH keep here so we can actually create a keep here manually in the UI here.
Let's call it server key player.
And the truth PEM format is a file format.
This is the one that you're going to need if you're working with Windows.
But I believe Panfilo also works for Windows, so let's create the one with him file, and as soon as
we created the PIN file, it's downloaded.
So basically what happens is that it has created a private public keep here and we have the private
key part in this file.
So we have to keep this file securely because this basically holds the information that we need to connect
or access the server.
Right.
So if you give it to someone else who shouldn't have access to S.H., they will actually be able to
access the server.
So you have to keep it in a secure place and you need to restrict the access and permissions on that
file.
So a best practice for keeping this pen file.
Actually, this private key is to move it from the downloads folder to your SSL dot SSL folder inside
your user folder.
So we can do that in terminal actually, so we can move.
And I know that it's in the downloads folder.
So wherever it got downloaded, basically you find it and this is the PIN file and we're going to move
it into this folder and.
So we have it and this is basically a secure place on your Internet to store private keys, basically
anything that should be restricted and not easily accessible for other users.
And another thing we should do on it is restrict the permissions.
So right now,
you see that he has read permission and write permission as well.
What we need to do is set it permission to be stricter and we're going to say it to four hundred and
let's execute.
Let's do it again.
And there you go.
We just let the permission for the owner, which is my user, and it is unacceptable for everybody else
and know that this step here is actually not optional.
It is required because whenever you use a pen file that doesn't have this strict access, eight of us
will actually reject the SSA request to the server.
So you will have to modify the permission of the pen file.
It is a required step.
So basically we just created a key player in us.
It got downloaded locally and we have saved it into a secure location in the age and we have restricted
its permission so that we only our user has a read only access to it so that we can use it for connecting
and researching into Isatou server.
Great.
So that step is done.
And no, we can use that key reference right here.
Right, because we have the key.
However, we have to associate that key with the server.
Right.
And we're going to do that using key name.
And the key name is basically the reference to this name right here.
Right.
So we are telling us associate the key called server.
Keep here.
With this specific instance, so we're going to hardcoded and there you go.
So in this association will basically make it possible for us to use that pen file to S.H. into our
instance.
Great.
And the only thing missing is the tag for named.
It's copied from here.
And let's call it the server, and now it's time to execute our configuration and create the easy two
instance with all of these attributes set.
So first, let's do a terraformed PLEN.
And again, terraformed plan basically tells us where we have an issue.
It seems like on one hundred five I forgot to put equal sign here.
So let's try again.
And these are bunch of attributes, for our instance, that we're creating right now, most of them
are not said, obviously, because they will be generated by abuse like public and private IP addresses,
host ID and bunch of other stuff.
But it looks good.
So we can do it here from a play and create the ISATOU instance.
And it will take some time because the server will be initializing what's actually called dashboard.
And refresh, and we have.
A running server which is still initializing and it's in the creation is complete.
However, it's still initializing.
So let's actually wait for that.
And if I click inside.
We're going to already see a bunch of values that have been generated, so in the summer you see the
IP addresses like private IP address and public IP address.
And as you see here, the private IP address, for Ishita instance, is from the range of subnet Seiter
block.
Right.
So our subnet has sided block defined at 10 zero, 10 zero and every ISATOU server, every instance
inside the summit will get IP address from that range.
And as you see or is it, for instance, has one of the IP addresses taken from that ranch.
So this is how it works.
And then we also have the public IP address because we defined the attributes to assign public IP address
to the instance.
And this will basically allow us to access the agent in that instance as well as access it from the
browser.
So it's refreshing in and there you go.
Status check is green.
It is fully initialized.
So now we can actually just SNH into it using our Peñafiel.
So I'm going to do it as a search and then we have to specify the PEM file using this flag.
This is the PIN file that got downloaded and then we have the user, which is the default user.
Obviously two instances on this Eversole Linux images and then we have the public IP address, which
we can grab from here.
And.
This is the end point, this is the key to the private key we associated with that instance, and if
I execute it, we'll have to prove and.
There you go.
And again, this is the private IP address, because we're inside the server right now, which is defined
here.
So two instance got created, it got initialized and we were able to access into it because we have
defined the key name association right here.