So the first thing we need to do is connect to our account and in terror form, whenever you want to
connect to a technology and start using its API to create resources inside, to configure it, to add
some stuff, etc., basically just interact with this technology, you know, as Jenkins database,
whatever it may be, first thing you need is a provider.
So provider in tier form is basically a program or code that knows how to talk to that specific technology.
And if we go to a TerraForm main page Embrose providers, here you see a list of providers that TerraForm
has.
And as I mentioned previously, TerraForm actually works well and integrates with lots of lots of different
technologies.
And this is basically how TerraForm integrates with them using providers.
And here you are going to see the list of all the providers TerraForm supports for all the different
technologies, and this is an interesting part here.
First of all, we see the most commonly used ones, as is obviously something that's tier form is widely
used for a very obvious reason for that is because working with A.W. is through command line or management.
Console is hard because it is so granular and modular and powerful that it's really difficult to work
with it manually.
So automating it over us makes perfect sense as well as we have every Google Cloud, Kubernetes and
so on.
Now, if we scroll down here, you see a bunch of other providers that are old by Hashi Corp, right?
So these are basically the providers again code program that knows how to talk to that specific technology,
right?
So this code here is written so that it can talk to Kubernetes so that you don't have to know how to
talk to Kubernetes API.
Same goes with us.
You don't have to know how to talk to either.
We use API.
This provider translates your TerraForm configuration to something that is API understand so we can
talk to AWB for you.
And as I was saying, these are basically bunch of providers talking to helm, talking to HDP, GitHub
console, lots of different technologies, all maintained and created by Harsha Corp and if I scroll
further down.
Here we have verified providers, and these are third party technology partners that have created these
providers and also actively maintain them.
And you also have community providers that are basically created by community members.
This could be teams of developers or individual developers that publish their providers to terraform
registry for others to use them as well.
This is also a huge list of different technologies.
And here it always says who is maintaining it or who is creating and very logically enough.
There are lots of different technologies that also want to be integrated in TerraForm.
So they create their own providers for their own projects or products so that TerraForm users can talk
to that API.
So we have artifact theory from JFrog itself because it's the product from them.
We have Heroku, Griffen, Lee nodes and so on.
Right.
But you also have providers that are just developed by some developers or DevOps engineers who want
integration with the tool.
For example, if we look for jenkyns provider, you see three different ones that are developed by different
companies or people.
So basically, this means that whenever you decide to use TerraForm for a specific technology, for
example, we want to use TerraForm to connect to AWG and create resources inside.
You can come here and provider section.
You can look up the provider for that technology and start using it.
So in this case, we are going to need us.
We're going to see other providers and how to use them later.
Let's actually click inside.
And here we have overview.
And what's also more important is documentation.
So here basically you have a bunch of examples and documentation of how to use the provider.
So, for example, because Jenkins isn't officially from Hoshi Corp, again, let's look for one.
Let's choose this one.
For example, you see the.
Statistics of how much it has been used, which versions, et cetera.
So, for example, if we go with this one, we can check the documentation for how to use a provider
as well as which resources are available.
Now I want to note here that TerraForm is really, really well documented.
So whenever you're looking for an example to create to orchestrate or automate some technology with
TerraForm, you can actually just look it up here and you will for sure find a documentation for it,
as well as to Google search, because they also have all of these very highly search optimized.
So you can directly Google all this stuff.
For example, if you want to create EC2 instance in TerraForm, you can basically search it in Google
and here you get immediately.
The first result is documentation to how to create, you know, use instance.
So they're very well documented as well as search, optimize.
So this is actually one of the best things about any technology if they have good documentation because
it makes using that technology way easier when they provide examples and explanation.
So we're going to be working a lot with the documentation itself and seeing example usages here.
And just so, you know, this is not a case with many different technologies.
So this is already an advantage that TerraForm has.
So let's actually close all this and let's go back to our first provider documentation.
So Somalis is actually use the A.W. as provider in our main road, TFR.
So first, I'm going to open the folder that we created tearful folder so that we have a view of all
the files inside that folder.
So this is going to be our working directory.
And in the main DOD file, we're going to write following code.
First of all, provider.
You know, you ask and you see the syntax highlighting already, and we're going to pass in configuration
that will allow TerraForm to connect to our IWC account.
So first of all, we're going to define the region.
And you can choose one of the regions from the list right here.
So this part is the name of the region, and you should choose the one which is closest to your geographic
location.
So I'm going to go with E.U.'S three for my case.
And we're going to define our exes key.
And.
Secret key.
Right here, and we're going to hardcoded for no later, I'm going to show you a best practice of how
to actually set the credentials in not having them directly in the code, because TerraForm being an
infrastructure is code tool basically will be used in its files will be checked in into a code repository
like it, for example, just like application code.
So we don't want the sensitive data hardcoded in there, but for now, we're going to write it directly
here.
And these are the X's key and secret key of the admin user that we created in our account.
And you remember that we downloaded the credentials file for that user and we have access key and secret
key in that credentials file so we can basically just copy directly from here.
So this is the access key.
And the secret key, so now using TerraForm will connect to the IWC programmatically using our admin
user with these credentials.
Of course.
So now we have basically told TerraForm with this code that we want to use A.W. as provider because
we are going to be working with IWC.
And we're telling TerraForm that in order to be able to connect to our IWC account, it will need these
credentials.
And this is the region that we are working in.
So no, that IWC is the name of the provider, so it has to be IWC.
And you may be wondering where I got these valleys from and how do I know what these attributes are
called again?
Is I told you?
You can find all of this document it in here.
For example, here we see the usage with credentials, access key and secret key.
So you can find the attribute names and all of this in the documentation.
No, as I told you, provider is basically a program.
It's a code that knows how to talk to IWC.
And when we install TerraForm, it doesn't come with this code automatically.
Simple reason is that because it has so many providers and you're just going to be using just a handful
of them, right?
You don't want your terraform to have all of these included because it's just going to be a lot of wasted
resources, right?
You're going to need a lot of space storage for all of this code.
So instead, it's actually modular.
So you, as a TerraForm user, decide, you know what I want to work with A.W. is incurring 80s and
maybe Jenkins.
So I'm going to install these three providers and I'm going to be working only with those three.
So that means that whenever we define a provider here, we need to install that code right because it
is currently not available locally.
Right.
You can compare it to the dependencies in programming languages, right?
We define dependency inside a build tools mean build configuration file, and then we actually need
to install the dependency by executing a command of the built all right, like npm install, for example.
So the same goes with TerraForm.
We have just defined which provider we want.
Now it's time to install that provider locally.
So the way we do that is using TerraForm in its comment.
So let's go back to the ED and I am inside the TerraForm folder, where mean door taf is.
So when I do terraform in it, TerraForm will look inside that folder where it makes including the comment
in and see that I have defined a provider, so it needs to install it.
So and that's also an important part because as you see, we need to execute this command inside that
folder.
So it is it actually matters where we execute terraform commands for right.
For example, if we have multiple projects with multiple terraform files or separate from each other,
then you have to go into the one that you want to execute the TerraForm comments.
So let's do TerraForm in it.
No.
And you see initializing the backend and provider plugins, and here you see finding latest version
of Harshit Corp IWC.
This is actually the provider name that we have defined, and because it is from Hoshi Corp itself,
we don't have to provide this Corp. slash before it is by default, and it just install the latest version
of that specific provider successfully initialized in no.
If we go back to our editor and here you see, we just had Maynard Taf in that folder, right?
And now we have two files that have been generated by TerraForm.
These are dot files.
So the hidden files, basically, you can see it here as well in the File Explorer.
If we do show hidden files this to God generated and this is actually a hidden folder.
So if we expand it, you see TerraForm provider IWC with the version that got installed.
So this is actually the code that has been downloaded that will then be talking to us for us.
So this is the provider code and this is a file that basically keeps track of which providers are in.
Stored locally, which versions we have and so on.
So if we add another provider, then it will appear in here and another entry will be made in this file.
And these are managed by TerraForm.
We don't do anything in there.
Now there is one more thing we need to do here and here, as you see in the interviews provided documentation,
we have a new syntax for TerraForm version.
Starting from zero point to 13, where we define globally in the TerraForm configuration, which providers
our TerraForm project uses, as well as defined the version of each provider.
And if I click on the use provider button here.
It gives me the actual code with the specific version of that provider, which is always the latest
version of the provider.
And I can basically copy and use this configuration in my TerraForm project, so I'll copy that part.
Go back to the project where we already have the provider configuration defined and pasted in here and
safe.
So now if we have multiple providers that we use in our TerraForm project, we can actually list all
of them here within the required providers block with their specific versions.
Now this is not required because as you saw, it works without this code as well.
Right, we were able to actually initialize our project and download the provider without having this
configuration.
However, it is a good practice to define this explicitly.
Another common thing related to this configuration is to create a separate file called Providers Dot,
for example.
And have these configuration.
Defined in these providers file.
And again, if we use multiple providers basically have them all listed here, and it makes perfect
sense, especially if you're using 10 or 20 providers in your project, so you can extract that whole
configuration into a separate file to keep your code clean.
Right, because this is basically the logic where you provision infrastructure and this is going to
be just the place where you define which providers your project is using with which versions.
So you have this separation in your code, and there is one more thing to understand regarding this
provider definition.
I mentioned that it works without this code as well.
And we saw that we could use the A-to-B as provider without explicitly defining it here.
However, it only works for providers which are part of the TerraForm registry.
So again, if we go back to the documentation, you see that this provider actually is hosted by Hashi
Corp itself and its official registry.
And Harshaw Corp has a list of official providers which are marked using this icon here.
However, there are other providers which are community providers.
There are not part of the TerraForm registry.
And for them, we would actually have to explicitly define this configuration.
Why?
Because this configuration actually defines the source or the location where TerraForm should look for
the provider code to download.
So we need to tell TerraForm this is the provider and please downloaded from this location, which in
this case for us is Hoshi Corp itself.
However, let's see what happens if we try to use a provider which is not in the TerraForm registry.
Let's say you want to provision infrastructure on Lenart platform instead of us, which is another cloud
provider.
And for that, of course, you go to terraform documentation and you search for Lenard Provider.
Which is a verified provider and not an official one, as you see with the.
I can hear.
And let's switch to the documentation and copy the code for using the provider itself.
So we have a little old provider defined, you know, if I try to do TerraForm in it.
You see an error message that says failed to query available provider packages, and right here you
see that it tries to find a leaner provider in Hershey Corp. registry.
And it says that it doesn't have such a provider in that registry.
And that's the error message because Lehnert provider isn't hosted there.
So exactly for that case, we need to explicitly define the source or location of the provider.
And again, moving back to the documentation, you see the code of how that can be defined either here
or in the U.S.
Provider Link We also get the latest version later specific version.
Copy that?
Find it here.
So now you see Lynn Code isn't in the Hershey core registry, but in a registry called Lehnert, and
we have a version as well.
And now if I do terraform in it again, TerraForm will be able to find that lehnert provider in the
correct location and then download the provider code for this version inside the TerraForm project.
So if I expand this now, we have Lehnert Providers code available locally, so that's basically what
you need to know about this specific definition of providers.
It is optional for official Hasher Corp providers, and it is mandatory for non-official ones.
However, it is a recommended way of defining providers.
Now a quick note here.
This is an updated part.
So in the next demos, you will not see these providers dot your file because we're not using any providers
from an official registry.
So don't let it confuse you and be aware that generally it's a good practice to have this defined.
So now that we have provider installed locally, what can we do with IWC?
How we can interact with IWC using provider?
And this is another important and interesting part.
Provider actually gives us access to the entire whole API of IWC.
So basically, whatever is possible to do with an API of a technology provider is giving us that possibility.
So if it is exposes different services and resources in those services, then we can interact with all
of them using the provider.
So through a robust provider, we actually now have access to every single service in IWC and the resources
of those services so we can do whatever we want in our account.
And if we go back to the documentation of provider of provider, in this case, here you see which resources
of IWC are actually exposed and which resources we can work with is a list right here.
So you have different services and different features here.
You see, we have SC, two SC are all of them listed here.
And if I expand this inside of the service, we have a bunch of resources.
We have the aim.
I have snapshots volumes.
So basically we can do whatever we want for easy to service.