Now that we have an AWB provider configured, we can actually start creating AWB resources using that
provider and throughout this course we will actually create a couple of these resources using terraform.
So before you move on with this tutorial, it's important to understand this AWB resources first.
So in this video, we're going to go through and understand what VPC and subnet resources are on us,
as well as Internet Gateway, Resource Security Group and so on.
If you already know these resources, then you can skip this video and go to the next one.
Now, whenever you create an account in each region, you will have something called a VPC.
So VPC actually stands for virtual private cloud.
So if you go through the service this year, all services list.
In the networking and content delivery part, we have this VPC service, and right now I'm in the Frankford
region and here you see I have a VPC, a default one that gets created with some other configuration
as well.
And if I switch to another region, for example, Europe, Perry's.
Here I also see a VPC, so I haven't created any of this.
This is out of the box by default in each region.
So VPC in Adewusi is basically your private network, right?
When you create resources, virtual servers and so on on us, you obviously don't want other US users
or other abuse accounts to have access to your resources.
Right.
You want to protect them and you want only you to have access to them.
So because of that, you can create this virtual private cloud on Adewusi infrastructure that only you
have access to and you create this VPC in a specific region.
So again, region is basically one of those regions in at least.
So, for example, in Perry's region, in the US three, I can create as many pieces as I want.
However, region in Adewusi consists of multiple availability zones.
Availability zone, in very simple words, is basically a data center of interviews with all those servers
that runs the whole infrastructure.
So the virtual machines that you spin up in your area will actually run in one of those, Azeez, because
these are the actual physical locations where the servers will run.
So VPC will actually spend all the availability zones in that specific region.
So here you see Perry's has three zones and VPC actually spends all of these three zones.
So in each region, basically, VPC isolates a space where you are creating your virtual instances,
your servers, maybe database instance, some other components from different services, because obviously
this is a data center where others also rent virtual servers, create components.
So they might actually be running on the same physical machine, same computer, but they will be isolated
in private networks with the PC's.
And for bigger corporations that have much more complex application setups, they can actually use multiple
vortices and manage multiple of these private networks in different regions.
Now, what does this VPC include here?
You see, we are in the VPC dashboard.
And we have a bunch of other stuff in here, it is basically a virtual representation of network infrastructure.
When you have servers physically in your company, which was a traditional way of hosting servers and
applications before cloud, you have CIS administrators that set up configure and manage this whole
network.
They set up the router, they do all the network configuration, configure firewall and so on.
So all of this physical network infrastructure is basically now moved in cloud and VPC is the representation
of this.
And the reason why you have this default VPC in each region is that whenever you create a new instance,
it has to run inside a VPC or whatever component you're launching.
It has to run, it has to start inside a VPC.
Another thing you see here is subnets.
So we have three summits in summits are subnetwork, so VPC is the whole private network and summits
are basically component's or sub networks of the VPC, while VPC spends the whole region, all the availability
zones, subnets spend individual availability zones.
So for each three zones, you have their own subnet.
So it's like a private network inside a network.
In other interesting thing in the BBC part is that obviously whenever you create a virtual server,
it has to get an IP address and in VPC you have a range of private or internal IP addresses in that
range is actually also defined by default and you can even change it.
So if I go inside VPC, you have a range of IP addresses.
So whenever you create a new instance, a new AC2 instance, an IP address will be assigned to it from
this range.
So internal or private IP address is not for Internet traffic, but rather for traffic inside the VPC.
So when you have multiple servers, multiple components inside the VPC, they need to communicate with
each other.
Right.
So you have an instance with Web application, in other instance with database application, maybe a
third one with some other service.
They all need to communicate.
So private IP address is what allows them to talk to each other.
So the IP address range is defined on a VPC level and then each subnet then gets its own IP address
range.
The private IP address range from that total range.
It gets like a sub range, so to say you see those sub ranges defined.
Now, obviously, when we deploy our Web application on Isleta instance, we want it to be accessible
from Internet right from outside.
And for that, in addition to private IP address, we need to assign it a public IP address.
And this is also configured in VPC service.
So when we create an easy to instance, it will get a private IP address from the range of the subnets
inside which that instance will start.
And it will also get a public IP address, internal one for internal communication inside the VPC and
a public IP address for accessing it through the browser for allowing Internet connectivity with your
VPC.
You also have an Internet gateway component.
So this basically connects VPC to Internet, to the outside world so that you can get traffic inside
your PC to your Web servers, for example, and then you can also send traffic outside if you want to
download some stuff from Internet on your components, et cetera.
Now, obviously, in addition to all of these network configuration, you need to secure your components,
right.
So, for example, you want to control what traffic enters your PC or what traffic reaches individual
instances and components in your PC or in your subnets.
And you want to control what traffic goes out.
Right.
So this is a firewall configuration basically for your PC and for individual instances.
Now, you can configure that security control on multiple levels in VPC.
And Adewusi makes it actually pretty flexible and granular of how you can configure all of this stuff,
not just security, but the IP address ranges, the row tables and so on.
And that's why you have this pretty big list of things that you can configure.
However, in many cases you will not need some advanced network configuration.
Most of the stuff is configured by default, as you see here, because you have these components already
created and configured with some default configuration.
And in most simple applications, you will not need to do any crazy configurations here.
And since this whole network is private and by default closed to the outside world.
So no access from Internet, of course, for your Web applications, you want to configure some Internet
access, right.
As well as you want to S.H. into your servers from your laptop.
So you want to configure some kind of external access.
And for that.
You have components inside that VPC service called Network ECLSS, which are basically firewalls or
firewall rules for subnets, so you can configure this per subnet.
And in addition to that, you have security groups which are, again, firewall rules, but on a virtual
machine level.
So inside the BBC, we have the subnet and inside subnets, we're going to have easy two instances,
which are basically the virtual servers, and we can configure firewall rules on that virtual server
level using security groups.
So you create both of these components on a VPC level and then you assign the Nichols' to individual
subnets and assign security groups to individual instances or components inside that VPC.