So now let's actually make some changes to our configuration, as you see, we haven't given names to
our resources, so basically our subnet doesn't have a name in our VPC, doesn't have a name either.
But it would be good to have a name to differentiate it from other resources.
So let's make the change in our configuration.
So again, we're telling TerraForm.
We want the desired state to be subnet with this configuration and a certain name and another subnet
with this configuration in some name and VPC and TerraForm needs to figure out what changes it needs
to apply to the current state to give us the new desired end result.
So how do we give names to the resources?
We do that by adding a parameter called Tiggs and as you know, takes our key value pairs in HWC and
you can agree to any resource in eight of us and you can have arbitrary key value pairs.
So basically you have the TEG key value here being my key, my value.
So basically these are the names that you can decide yourself.
For example, this is the VPC environment for developers, whatever.
However, there is one key attribute reserved for a name, and that is name.
So if we specify a name tag and set it to some value, that's Sedita development.
Basically, this will be assigned as a name and it will appear right here.
And we're going to do the same for the subnets as well.
And takes are basically something that you can define for any resource.
So this attribute exists for all the resources and let's say subnet one, then.
And let's say they is subnets default, whatever, this is, the default subnet.
In actual scenarios, you will have maybe more descriptive names here, and we can also add another
take here and let's actually call it VPC Environment and Death and save it.
And now if we do terraform it put.
We have a bunch of output here, so let's actually go through the changes and see what happened here.
So first of all, you see another icon here with a slightly yellowish color, which is the tilt character.
So basically plus was for creating a resource untilled is for a change.
So this means that we are changing an existing resource and a subnet resource with the subnet one name.
And inside that resource, we're changing the text attribute and we're adding a new tech, which is
a name.
And you also see that we have eight other attributes that will be unchanged.
And the same goes for this resource and for VPC we are adding to text.
So tilt is for change, right?
We're changing an existing resource.
And if we enter.
Yes.
TerraForm will execute all the changes, and now if we go back to our areas, console and refresh,
you see the name development appeared here as well as in the Tiggs section.
Right.
So these are list of takes that we can assign as many takes as we want.
And also in the VPC, we have a subnet name which also has text.
Now, what happens if we want to remove something from an existing resource?
Let's say we want to remove this take here and now if we apply.
You see another character, which is minus and it is in red color, so basically, again, TerraForm
went ahead and calculated what is the current state?
The current state was basically this.
Right.
And it gets the current state from us.
And since we remove these terraform correctly decided that the current state needs to be updated by
removing this tag from the VPC resource on Adewusi.
And the minus basically means removal or deletion.
And this is again where we are changing a resource.
And inside that resource we're removing a tick so we can apply that as well.
And if we refresh our VPC.
And go to.
The text has been removed.
Now, what if we wanted to remove the whole resource, let's say we don't want this subnets to anymore?
Now, there are two ways of removing a resource that we don't need any more.
One option is to remove the resource from terraform file.
Right.
So if we basically just remove this again, TerraForm will compare the current state, which is we have
a subnet in default VPC and the desired DRC, which is no subnet resource specified for default.
VPC TerraForm will decide this resource need to be removed.
So if we do terraform, play again.
Here you see that the whole resource is marked with minus because this resource will be removed, of
course, including all the attributes.
Now let's actually type in whatever something other than yes and apply will be canceled and revert this.
Now, the second option to remove a resource is using TerraForm Command.
Terraformed, destroyed in passing in the resource name, right?
So we are specifically removing this resource right here and we are passing in a target because we are
dealing with a single resource.
And the way we provide the target name is by the resource type.
And resource me, all right, so we have the resource type given by provider and the name that we gave
resource ourselves and this will tell terraformed to destroy this one specific resource.
So let's actually execute this.
And again, similar to terraformed a play, we see the same output, which tells us that the subnets
to resource will be destroyed.
Again, in summary, one to destroy.
And we have to confirm this action.
Let's actually confirm and say yes.
And destroy comp. So if we refresh this list, here we go, the fourth subnet is gone.
Now, you're probably asking which of these two options is the way to go?
Which one you should use?
And the answer to that is actually terraform.
Why?
Because if you destroy specific targets using TerraForm, Destroy Command and with target tech, you
end up with a configuration file that doesn't actually correspond to the current state because you still
have that resource inside your configuration file.
And especially if you're working with a team and you destroy or change resources using commands and
not the configuration file, you basically have a difference between the current state and what's in
the configuration file.
And again, is a best practice of infrastructure is code.
Code should represent the changes made to the infrastructure and the resources.
So all the changes should be made through the configuration files.
So I would suggest you to use terraform apply and to make the changes through configuration files instead
of comments directly.