Now, let's say you have a configuration file and you want to check the difference between the current
state and your configured state, and basically you don't know what the current state is because there
are multiple people working on the project and you just want to see the difference.
And you don't want to do terraform a man.
You just want to see the difference between current and desired state.
For that, you can actually execute TerraForm PLEN Command, which is like a preview.
Same as what TerraForm Apply Command gives you, but without the actual applying it.
So here you see that just like with appli command, you get this list of actions that TerraForm will
execute in order to get you to the desired state.
And as we have deleted some to using terraformed destroy command, but we still have it in the configuration
file.
It basically tells us in terraformed plan that a new resource would be added if you would execute,
terraform, apply.
Now, if you are executing TerraForm, Play Command, however, you don't want to always confirm the
execution or wait for terraformed to calculate all the changes and then confirm the change.
You just want to automatically approve any change you can pass in order to approve Flik.
And this will basically.
Apply immediately without waiting for your confirmation.
And here, as you see, the preview wasn't given and I wasn't asked for confirmation and the change
got applied immediately, we have resources, one added.
So we have created back our subunit in a default VPC.
Now, what if I wanted to completely destroy my infrastructure and everything that I have created using
this configuration file?
I wanted to clean everything up for that.
We can actually execute, terraform, destroy command.
And if we do not provide any targets as parameter, it will basically fund our terraform configuration
file.
It will go through all the resources and destroy or basically just remove all the resources one by one
in the correct order that we have defined here.
So let's execute it now.
We get a preview of.
What gets destroyed so all three elements or resources will be removed and we can actually confirm this
action in TerraForm will clean everything up.
Now, this command is actually handy and can be used if you want to revert exactly what you have created
with this configuration file.
And unlike destroy with a specific target, terraform, destroy, which destroys the whole infrastructure
is actually pretty convenient because you don't have to worry about in which order and sequence you
have to destroy.
The resources.
TerraForm will figure out which one depends on which and it will basically clean everything up.
So if you're testing something with TerraForm, if you're playing around with resources, then terraform,
destroy.
It will be pretty handy way of just cleaning everything up that you have created.
So now if I go to my account and refresh the boxes, you see the VPC is gone as well as.
The subnet one def, if I refresh it here, is gone as well.
So all the resources have been removed.