Now, I mentioned several times that Terraformed keeps track of the current state and reads the desired
state from the configuration file, right.
So every time we do terraform a play or we have done terraform a play or destroy it in the output's,
we have the refreshing state messages.
Right.
So for the resources that are available in the configuration file or we have defined here, TerraForm
refreshes the state and then it calculates in the background whether anything needs to be done in order
to get from the current state to the desired state.
Now, how does TerraForm know what the current state of the resources defined here is?
Now, if you look in that terraform folder that we have, our main thought file in, two additional
files have been generated by TerraForm and these are called terraformed dot T.F. State and TFSA dot
pickup.
So this is a JSON file basically that gives us a list of resources in their current state.
And TerraForm generates these files on the first appli.
Right.
The first time we execute TerraForm Inplay Command TerraForm actually goes to HWC because that's our
provider.
It connects to our account, it executes whatever we define in the configuration state, and then it
stauss the current state in this terraform state file.
And whenever we make changes and we apply these changes, this terraformed file gets updated.
So basically this is like a state store for TerraForm to get that up to date information and this refreshing
output that you see here.
What this basically does is refreshing this file and setting new information here because we have destroyed
all our resources.
Right now, the resources is an empty array.
So current state basically is we have none of the resources that are defined here in the AWB account.
And the backup file is actually the previous state for the resources.
So before we deleted all our resources, this was a state, the previous state, with all the information
here and it is saved, is a backup to have a previous state as well.
So now let's go back to our TFSA, which shows that the resources is empty and let's now actually reapply
this whole configuration.
So let's do terraform play, let's actually do or proof so that we don't have to confirm it.
So Terraformed says that the current state is basically empty resources, so it compares it to the desired
state and it creates all the resources that we have defined.
Right.
And these are basically the names of the resources with resource type and resource name that we gave
it.
And now if we go back to our.
Terraformed state file, you see, the empty array of resources has been filled in with new information
and each element inside this resources arena is basically one configuration, resource and component
we have defined here.
So first we have data.
This whole thing here that stores the information that we get as a result of querying these existing
VPC.
So we have the default VPC information here in data, VPC, existing VPC objects.
And since this is a default VPC, we have attributes associated to that.
VPC, right.
We have the answer.
We have the site or blog of the default VPC and so on.
As a next object, we have a subnet dev subnet one again with all the attributes of that subnet that
we're all pfeg from Adewusi and stored in here and we have another subnet and the VPC that we created.
So all our four components.
Right.
All these four are stored in the state and in the backup we have again, the previous state, which
was empty resources before we reapplied our configuration.
And as I said, TerraForm uses these files here to manage the state and update the current state in
order to know what changes need to be done to take us from the current state to the desired state.
And obviously, looking into this terraformed state, especially if we have hundreds of resources created
in our account, is going to be pretty difficult, especially if we are just interested in some of the
attributes and we don't want to see the whole object with all the attributes.
TerraForm actually has comments so that we can access the information inside the state.
So let's go back to the command line.
And if I do terraform state and just return, you see all the subcommanders of terraformed state we
have available so we can list all the resources that are in the state.
So we have again.
For resources, we have the resource type.
And resource name, as well as whether it's coming from Edyta, we can also show a specific resource,
for example, this one right here.
And all this configuration to that specific resource in the output, and this can be actually a very
useful command because in the configuration file itself, we are just defining a handful of attributes.
The rest of them get generated by us.
Right.
So if you want to know the attribute values for the other attributes that A.W. sets, instead of going
to the management console and finding that specific resource and then checking its attributes, we can
just print it out here.
So, for example, if we want the year end of the resource or the ID which gets generated by us, we
don't set this.
We can easily look it up in here.
In other news, case could be if we're creating an easy two instance that gets a public IP address assigned
to it automatically by us, we want to get that IP address and we can actually check it using TerraForm
Stage Show Command for our easy to resource.
So there are multiple use cases where we would need to check some information about a resource we just
created.
And we had a bunch of other commands like pulling the current state from us, as well as making changes
in the state, which most of the time we shouldn't directly interact and update the state or update
these file ourselves manually.
It should be done by terraform itself as a result of applying our configuration.
And if I remove this resource, let's say using terraformed destroy command or by just removing it from
here and apply, let's remove this one as well.
And let's do terraform applied with or approve.
You see, that state got up to date and two components got deleted and in the state file, we now have
just two components as well as if I do terraformed state list.
These are the two components left in our state.