Another interesting feature of TerraForm is actually it allows us to output a set of attributes and
the values of the resources we just created.
So as you already saw, we are creating resources with just a handful of attributes and the rest of
the attributes get actually generated by us.
And you saw that we can actually see those generated attribute values once we create the resources either
in the terraformed state file or using terraform state shows Subcommander for a specific resource.
Right.
In other words, you outputs a specific attribute of a resource we just created in the resource that
we have defined ourself is using outputs values.
So inside the configuration file we can actually define what value we want terraform to output at the
end of applying our configuration from one of the resources.
And we do that by creating output values.
So we have the outputs key word here and we are going to give this output value in name.
And let's say in our example, we want to output the ideas of every resource that we are creating.
So we want the idea of the VPC as well as a subnet that gets created in each of us.
So first, I'm going to destroy.
Those two resources
by executing, terraformed, destroying.
So both of them are removed and they're removed from the state as well.
And now we are going to recreate them in output ID of each of those two resources.
So output first one will call it VPC Edem or let's call it the PC Edem.
And in the block, we want to tell terraformed which attributes value.
We want it to output.
Right.
So we have the whole object here.
So we have the PC resource type development VPC resource name and this is the whole object, whole PC
object and we want to output the ID of that resource.
Now, again, if you want to check which attributes are available for each resource, we can actually
do a terraform coin.
Which will show us a preview of terror forms, planned actions, including the attributes that either
we set or interviews will set for that resource.
And you can actually choose one of the attributes from here to be displayed.
In our case, we're choosing Edem of the subnet and ID of VPC pretty straightforward.
These are called IDs on all the resources.
So this will be our first output and we are going to define a second output as well.
So let's call this the subnet I.D. and this is going to be US subnet resource type that the subnet one
and I did.
And for each attribute you actually have to define its own output.
So you can't have multiple values here even from the same exact resource.
So one output value for each attributes we want to output.
So let's actually save this and apply.
It's true or a proof.
And here you see, before we had this employee status, now we have output's additionally, and this
gives us our output values.
These are the names of our output values, what we call them here.
And these are the actual.
Values we have referenced right here, and this is obviously handy, if you are creating resources,
maybe a bunch of resources and you want to have ideas of all of them, you can just print it out like
this.
Or as I said previously.
Another example is if you are creating server instances and you want their public IP addresses etc,
you can just output it like this so you don't have to do a state show or look into the state file to
find this information.
You have it nicely printed out in here.