Another interesting concept of terraform is variables, so you can actually use variables inside the
configuration file.
So, for example, let's say we want a value of site or blog not to be hard coded here, but we want
to pass it as a parameter.
In this case, we can actually define a variable for this site or blog and then reference that variable
and its value right here.
And this can be pretty handy, especially if you have values that are used multiple times for different
resources or if you want to reuse the configuration files of terraform for multiple different environments
and you want to pass in different parameters for different use cases.
Right.
For example, have the same template for development and production environments where you can basically
just define all these values like naming, etc. as parameters and proceed from outside.
So what we're going to do is to make it very simple.
We're going to use a variable for site or block of the subnet.
So I'm going to remove it right here.
And the variables in TerraForm are defined with a variable keyword and we're going to name the variable
whatever we want.
Let's actually call it subnet, slider, block.
And inside that variable definition, we have a possibility to define several attributes.
And we're just going to go with the description that basically describes what the variable is about.
And we can basically just repeat that slider block and this defines our variable.
And now we can use that variable as a value right here in the way we do that is using VAR.
Dot and the variable name, so as I see, the syntax is really consistent throughout, so whether we're
defining resource or data or variable, the actual syntax is actually pretty similar.
Right.
We have the key word and have the name and we have this block where we pass in parameters and and also
referencing resources or data or variables.
It's all pretty consistent, right, for data.
We had data dot name of that data for variable.
We have our dot variable name.
So we have defined a variable and we have referenced that variable right here.
However, we haven't assigned a value to our variable and this should actually be equals sine.
Now, there are three ways of assigning a value to a variable.
So the first way to assign a variable value is when we do terraform a play,
we get a prompt for entering the slider block.
Right.
So this is the variable name reference and we're expected to enter a value.
Let's actually do 10 dot zero.
Dot 20.
And here you see the changes that will be made, because we actually have both of these resources,
VPC and subunit existing, so we are making a change to the site or blog.
So what we see in terraform output is that the subnet will get removed and then recreated because we
are making change to the site block.
And if we do.
Yes.
The old subnet got destroyed because you can change the cinder block on an existing subnet, so it removed
the old one and create a new one with a new idea.
And if we go to us, this was the old subnet and refresh.
This is the new one with a new Seiter block.
So this is one way to assign variable.
But this is obviously not an efficient way.
This could be for testing or just trying out a new value.
However, for long term, if you want to automate your processes, we have to define the variables without
having a user prompt.
So the second way of passing in a variable is using command line argument in TerraForm Applied.
So if we do terraform apply and we're leaving the configuration as is because the variable is still
not assigned, so we can actually assign it again with terror from a play minus four and is an argument
we can pass in the name of the variable, which is this name right here, and the value which let's
agree to something different, let's do 30 zero.
And now if I execute this.
We see the same output.
So basically the site or blog needs to be changed from this to the new one that we defined.
So the subnet will be destroyed and a new one will be created.
So this time we're not prompted for an input.
And if we do, yes.
And refresh.
There you go, a new subnet got created with a new block and there is a lust and actually the most efficient
or the most correct way of assigning values to variables.
And this is actually a best practice that you should be using most of the time.
And the third way is defining variables file and assigning values to all the variables for your terraform
configuration inside that file.
And that file in TerraForm actually has its own naming convention and file ending.
So let's create this file and the name, the default name which Terraformed will automatically find
and recognize is a variables file is terraform dot T.F. Varas.
So let's enter so the file ending or extension must be to force, and if we name file terraformed,
telephone will be able to automatically find and recognize it as a force or variables file.
And inside this file, we can define key value pairs for our variables.
So we have the variable name equals the value of that variable.
And in this case, let's actually set it to zero 40 zero twenty four and save it and know if we apply
that.
And we don't need to pass in a variable option or enter a value as a prompt telephone will basically
automatically find that variables file and read the variable value from that file and set it here.
So let's see.
There you go.
We have the review that the Seiter blog is getting changed from this to this value that we have defined
in the T.F. versus file.
And we can confirm.
And there you go.
Let's refresh here we have the new site or blog.
So as I said, this is actually the correct way or a way that you should be using in most of the cases
for assigning variables.
And obviously, you can define multiple variables in here.
Let's actually extract this as well as a variable.
And let's call it VPC cinder block.
And we're going to reference it again with four VPC spider blog and by the way, this autocomplete that
I get here is from the plug in, the terraformed plug in that I have installed in my visual code, which
helps a lot in typing.
So we have a second variable, which is called VPC Spider Block.
So PC Spider Block, we can assign a value that was originally stated, but set it here instead.
And this way we can actually make the whole configuration or almost all of the configuration parameterized
and reuseable so that depending on the use case, we can pass in the respective values.
One of the cases for that is if we have a configuration file or multiple configuration files that create
a bunch of resources and basically just create the whole infrastructure with the VPC and security groups,
et cetera.
And if we want to replicate the same exact infrastructure is, let's say, a development environment,
a staging environment and production environment, we can have this configuration files for all three
environments and then change parameters based on which environment we are in, for example, names.
So basically just referencing as environment.
So we would have a variable called environment and.
We can describe it is, let's say, deployment.
Environment and then define these values in the variables file, and you would do the same for all the
other techs and also make the resource names more generic, like my PC instead of development PC, so
that the configuration is reusable for different environments.
And based on which environment you're applying to, you would basically substitute the value.
Now, in this case, you would have variable files for all three environments, right?
You would have variables file for development, production and staging.
So this would be terraformed.
Dev, for example, and all the values for development environment will be set here.
And then you would have terraform productive workers, for example, with all the product values.
Now, if we change the name of these variables, file from terraformed to something else.
In this case, terraform dash dev, then we need to pass the filename as a parameter when we apply.
So now if we do terraform a play without passing in the file name, see, it prompts us for the variable
value, right?
Because TerraForm cannot find a variables file because it's looking for terraformed or worse.
So let's actually just break it and import the apply.
So instead we do that by setting a flag for file and the name of the file that we are passing in our
case, terraformed Dev thought T.F. words and apply.
And as you see, terraformed was able to get the variables defined here, so it didn't prompt us for
input, and since we didn't make any changes, there is nothing to apply.
So, like, complete with no changes.
So this is how you can use variables in your configuration file and how you can make your configuration
of resources reusable for different environments, for different use cases by passing in variables,
using these variables file.
So I have removed all the variables except for the subnet cinder block, and there are two more characteristics
or things to explain about variables.
The first one is that we can assign variables, default values.
So inside this block here, we can do default.
And default attributes will get a value, let's say, three to zero, 10 zero.
Let's say this is the default value and here we have a value defined for Seiter blog is 10 zero, 15
zero.
Now, the default value will kick in if TerraForm cannot find value defined for that variable either
in the variables file or is a command line parameter.
In this case, it will not prompt you for a value.
It will just take the default.
Right.
So if we remove it here or basically we just didn't provide the terraform def file name, then this
value will be taken.
And this is also pretty handy if you have the configuration that should work is a default set up and
then you allow different users for different use cases to pass in parameters to override the default.
So for example, development configuration could be the default and then you would have variable files
for other environments or it could be production and then you have development and staging variable
files.
And the second thing you can do with variables is set a variable type, right?
So we have the type attribute which can have multiple different values.
It could be a boolean, it could be string, it could be a number.
So, for example, for the site or blog, it is a string.
And maybe for most of the cases you will need a type or you may just leave it blank.
However, if you have some value that has to be of a certain type and you want the users of your configuration
files that basically pass in values through the variables file, for example, or as command line option,
you want them to know that this variable has to have this type.
So you kind of enforce that for the users.
So you have the option of setting a type for your variables.
So in this case, if someone passed in an array, for example, instead like this, then TerraForm will
give an error because it expects string.
Let's actually try this out.
And there you go, invalided valley for input variable because it needs to be a string, so string required,
but we are passing it right, or at least so let's say that we want this variable to be at least that
contains multiple CITA blocks.
Right.
In this case, we can define the type is a list of strings and let's actually remove the defaults.
And let's say these are just seiter blocks for VPC and subnets.
And let's call it Spider Block's.
And no, it expects us to give a list of cinderblocks, so I'm going to copy the name that said it here
and we can pass in.
The values, right, let's say the first one is 10 zero zero zero, that's what we had for.
The VPC, and this is for each one of its subnets and let's actually set it to 10 and now we have a
variable which holds a list, so we have to change how we reference that variable.
First of all, let's change the name.
And second of all, this will basically give us the whole list.
Right.
So insider blog in subnet, we need the second element.
So with Vado outsider blogs, we're referencing the whole list.
Right.
But we just need the second element of that list so we can access it by using very simple list syntax
with an index of one.
This is the second element.
And then we're going to have cinderblocks, blocks, index of zero.
This is the first element is a VPC block, right.
So the first one is VPC.
Second one is subnet.
And let's execute it.
And there you go, we see that.
Subnets will get replaced because we didn't change the IP range of VPC, so it will stay the same and
we can confirm it.
So now our subnet has a new Seiter block.
We can also have objects as variables in terraform.
So for example, here, instead of strings or instead of list of strings, we can actually have a list
of objects as well.
So let's say this is a cinder block attribute and then we have name attribute, for example, and let's
call it the VPC.
And the same here.
Dave Subnet.
So basically, we have a list of objects right here, and each object here has seiter block, attribute
and name attribute and of course now we have to adjust the usage of this variable in May not T.F. So
first of all, we could also validate a list of objects using a list of object type like this.
So obviously, if you just had object, you could do this.
But we have a list of objects and you can validate the object attributes inside as well.
So you could do this.
And then we have two attributes set a block and we can say this needs to be a string and we have a name
which also needs to be a string.
So this way we can actually validate the whole object and we can say this should be a list of objects
with these attributes which have string type.
Again, a use case for this is if you are creating configuration files and then you let other team members
maybe use those configuration files by passing in different parameters as variables.
So you may want to restrict or give them guidelines to what values they can pass in as parameters.
So basically you can define this type here if you just leave it empty.
Basically, they can put in whatever type they want.
So let's set the type for it.
And now we have to access the variable values differently.
So accessing the first element will be done with this.
So say blocks index zero.
So basically we're fetching the first element, which is the whole object here.
Right.
It's not just citable value, but it's the whole object.
So in order to get the cinder block value out of it, we have to reference the object attributes.
So we're going to do dot site block.
And then we also have name defined.
Right, so we can access the name.
Using the name attributes like this, and we could do the same right here.
So, look, you see, I have autocomplete suggestion as well as name attribute right here.
And this will be a variable that has seiter blocks and names or name tags for VPC and subnet.
So these are a couple of different ways of how to use variables in TerraForm.