Now, as I mentioned at the beginning, writing the credentials directly in the configuration file is
actually not a good security practice because you're going to be checking this file into a git repository,
probably.
So you don't want your credentials to be checked in into a git repository so you can hard code these
values in here.
So first of all, let's actually remove them from here.
Let's just leave region.
And there are two ways that we can set these credentials for any user so that Terraformed can pick it
up.
The first one is setting these credentials as environmental variables.
So let's go back to the terminal.
And here we're going to set environmental variables that terraform then will pick up.
So the first variable is A.W. is secret exos key.
And this is, by the way, the same exact environmental variable that we need to set for using a command
line interface.
So this is the same for NWC itself.
And the value for this is.
We don't need the quotes, and the second one is eight of us excess key Edem.
And no, if we do terraform play.
You see, the terraformed was able to connect to us, even though we don't have credentials in the configuration
file for provider block here so we can actually report this.
I have to, right?
No, it can be anything other than.
Yes, so.
This is basically one way of setting credentials for us in this case specifically so that Terraformed
can authenticate with us.
However, if I now switched to another terminal window and did exporting environmental variables and
let's grab us, you see that those two environmental variables are not set here because they are only
accessible or available in this context.
Right.
So I have this environmental variable set here, but they're not available here anymore.
So if you want to have a globally configured in credentials, then you need to configure them in the
home directory, DOT AWB directory and you have credentials.
Right.
So so basically, if you have your credentials here, which is where AWB stores them, which is a default
location for storing it, credentials on any operating system, then TerraForm can also pick it up.
And the way to set these credentials is using it as configure.
And then you can basically type in the existing ID here, then secret key ID as well as default region.
I already have set these values.
So they're basically the existing values that I'm seeing here.
If you're doing it for the first time, there will be empty.
So you have to provide some value.
And when you do configure and enter all these values, this DOT NWS directory will automatically get
generated with credentials and config files inside and there will be basically your global energy user
credential configuration.
So if I did terraformed apply with a variable file.
Therefore, they've thought to was.
TerraForm should be able to use the credentials in area with US credentials file and still be able to
authenticate with eyewitness account.
And there you go.
We see that output.
Let's actually do.
Yes.
So if TerraForm can connect to the airwaves account, it will not be able to refresh the state because
it needs to fetch the state, the current state from the eatery's account to compare it to our desired
state and decide what action needs to be taken.
So here you see it play complete.
The changes were applied.
So you should use one of these two ways to configure credentials for AWEX or any other technology that
you are connecting with could be Google Cloud or it could be a jenkins' server or communities.
So instead of typing it or hard coding it into the config file, you should set it either as environmental
variables and you will see in the documentation of each provider which environmental variables supported,
as well as which are the ways of setting the credentials from outside is supported.
So, for example, let's look up Jenkins' here.
And documentation.
And there you go, for example, you have the server, your username and password, and you have again
enviromental variable names that you can set as an alternative to hard coding the values here.
So that terraformed can pick up these values to authenticate with Jenkins', as well as some detailed
documentation about the authentication.
So it should work the same no matter which provider you're using.
And also know that you can also configure region by setting environmental variable.
Because in my account on my laptop locally, I have also configured the default region.
So if I'm using the default one, I can just basically just leave it empty and basically have the users
who are using this terraformed configuration set the region by setting the default region in order to
variable.
Now, what if you wanted to define your own custom environmental variables, can you do that in TerraForm?
In fact, TerraForm lets you set global environmental variables using T.F. underscore var prefix.
So let's say we want to work in one specific availability zone and we want that value to be set as a
global environmental variable.
Right.
So you could set environmental variable called T.F. Underscore for underscore and this could be any
name that we want to give that variable.
Let's say this is availability zone.
And this is the value and know that there should not be space around this equals sign when setting environmental
variables.
So this will now give us environmental variable called TFR and we'll zone.
And the way we can now reference that environmental variable inside terraformed configuration file is
using this part right here.
So this prefix basically tells terraformed.
This is a global variable and this is the name of the variable we can reference.
So I'm going to copy that.
Just the name of the variable without the prefix and we're going to declare it is a variable right here.
And let's just leave it empty.
No description or type, and we can now reference it and its value using a normal variable.
So var levels on and we're setting this value basically using.
Custom environments, a variable of terraform and know if we do terraform, apply again.
You see the terraformed got that variable from here, and since we didn't make a change, nothing got
applied.
Now let's actually set the variable value to three B, so this will basically tell terraformed to create
a subnet in availability zone three B, so that's, you know, terraformed play.
And and here you see that Dev summit one will be moved from three a availabilities on to three B C,
we can confirm that.
If we go back to our comment line and refresh the subnet.
You see that it's now in AISI three peat, so basically this is how you can also use custom tear form
in order to be able to set terraformed variable from outside and then reference it like a regular variable.
Or we could also say this is another way of setting a variable value in terraform.