Welcome to the TerraForm course, since TerraForm is an infrastructure as code tool before jumping into
the TerraForm itself.
First, let's understand what exactly the infrastructure as code concept means.
What are the different infrastructure as code tools and how is TerraForm different from them in the
past?
Way, way back before automation, when you wrote an application and wanted to deploy that on server
for that, you would go and get some servers, set them up, configure networking on those servers,
create round tables, install all the necessary software, configure the software and maybe install
the Java version you needed if you had Java application installed, database for application and do
all sorts of things to prepare the servers in order to make your application able to run on that server.
And all these things would be done manually by system administrators.
So you had a high human resources cost, as well as more effort and time and also a higher chance of
human error.
No, that will be just the setup fees, right?
But after the setup, you also have the maintenance.
Maybe you need to update the Java version and deploy the new release of your application.
Do database backups where updates recover your application after it crashed its servers or recover servers
after they crashed.
Changed networking configuration.
All sorts of things.
Again, all these would have been manual effort, and if you had test and production environments,
you would of course then have to do all these things on both environments.
Now, instead, in today's DevOps world, you don't have to do all this manually, and you can actually
automate the complete process thanks to infrastructure as code also abbreviated as a C.
So what is infrastructure?
Is code?
It's super simple.
It's a way of automating all of these tasks end to end instead of doing it manually.
So all the knowledge and expertise of system administrators and operations team packed into various
programs or applications that carry out all these tasks.
So infrastructure is code is a concept and their infrastructure is code tools or these specific programs
like Instable Puppet TerraForm Cloud Formation and many more that you can use for different tasks.
You may be asking Why do we have so many different tools?
Can we just use one infrastructure as code tool that does everything?
Well, currently there is no one.
Infrastructure is code tool that can do everything from start to finish.
So each tool can do parts of this automation tasks, which means each one is good in their own specific
area.
So to get an overview, there are three main categories of such tasks.
One, there is provisioning of infrastructure, which is the very first step.
This is spinning up fresh new servers, doing the network configuration on them, creating load balancers
and configuring all this other stuff on the infrastructure level.
The next step or category would be configuring the already provisioned infrastructure, like installing
applications and software on the servers and managing those applications.
This step would be needed to prepare the infrastructure or the servers with all the necessary stuff
to deploy your own application.
As I mentioned at the beginning, this could be installing Java or a database or any other service or
process your application needs.
And the third step would be actually deploying your application on that provisioned and configured infrastructure,
which is actually the main reason why you were doing all this setup.
I must mention here that with Docker container technology, the configuration and deployment steps kind
of merged together because with Docker, you basically take your application and all the configuration
it needs and package it together with the needed environment.
So you have the configuration already in the image itself.
So if you provisioning infrastructure and installed Docker runtime, you don't need to configure much
on the servers or install some services there.
You just run Docker containers, and that's it.
Another important point here is the distinction between initial setup and maintaining phases in these
categories.
So you provision and configure infrastructure the first time.
That's the first initial setup.
And afterwards you have the maintenance phase.
So you do adjustments to the infrastructure.
You change stuff.
You edit servers.
You remove servers.
You change network configuration, cetera.
Same way you do initial installation and configuration of software and then you have the maintenance
phase of that.
Software updates, changes, reconfiguration, all sorts of things.
So the difference between the infrastructure as code tools is that they automate tasks in different
categories for different phases in those categories.
So in most cases, you would use a combination of two or more tools to automate the whole process into
end.
So, for example, TerraForm is a tool to provision and then manage the infrastructure, but can also
be used for the initial installation or configuration of software on that infrastructure, but not for
further maintenance of that software.
On the other hand, Zibo chef puppet tools can be used to configure and deploy applications and also
manage them afterwards, as well as do some tasks of configuring an already provisioned infrastructure.
But it can be used to provision the initial set up of servers.
Therefore, a common example is people using TerraForm to provision infrastructure and configure it
and then use instable to install and deploy applications on that provisioned infrastructure.
There's also a difference between those tools in the way they work, among others.
These differences are declarative versus procedural approach with procedural.
You're right, step by step.
What you need to be executed like create a server in a server, etc. with declarative approach, you
declare what you want as an end result.
I want to servers.
Another difference is mutable infrastructure versus immutable, immutable being.
You create three servers, then you edit one change network configuration.
Maybe you remove two servers, whatever.
So you make those changes with immutable infrastructure instead of adding and removing or doing changes.
You always create a new one and discard the old so you always replace instead of changing.
There are also agents versus agent list tools, master versus master list and some other differences.
So maybe depending on your preferences and needs, you can choose the right tool.
And that is essentially the reason why we have multiple infrastructure as code tools instead of just
having one.
And in this course, we're going to learn about the most popular infrastructure provisioning tool,
TerraForm.
So let's get started.