So first of all, what is there for TerraForm allows you to automate and manage your infrastructure
and your platform and services that run on that infrastructure, it's open source and it uses declarative
language, meaning you don't have to define every step of how this automation in management is done.
You just clear what you want.
The final results or end results and TerraForm will figure out how to execute it versus imperative style,
where you specify how to execute each step.
So, as I said, terraform is a tool for infrastructure provisioning.
So what does that mean exactly?
Let's say you just started a project where you create some application and you want to set up an infrastructure
from scratch where this application will run.
How does your infrastructure look like?
Let's say you want to spin up several servers where you will deploy your five micro service applications
that make up your application as docker containers.
And also you are going to deploy a database container.
You decide to use A.W. as platform to build your whole infrastructure on.
So a first step will be to go to us and prepare the set up so that applications can be deployed there.
This means you create your private network space.
You create an employee easy to server instances.
You install Docker on each one of those, plus any other tools that you might need for your application.
You set up security on your servers like firewalls, you set up network, etc. Once the infrastructure
is prepared, you can now deploy your docker applications or docker containers on that prepared infrastructure.
So as I said, these are two different tasks or two to separate steps or creating the whole setup.
One is provisioning the infrastructure, preparing everything so the application can be deployed.
The second one is actually deploying the applications on it.
So you might even have two separate teams or two individuals who do these two separate tasks.
So possible scenario develops, team member configuring the infrastructure and a developer then deploys
the applications on the prepared infrastructure.
So where does TerraForm come into this whole thing?
TerraForm is used for the first part where you provision the infrastructure to prepare it for the application
deployment, creating the PC, spinning up the servers, creating the security, the user with permissions,
maybe installing Docker specific version on servers, et cetera.
And obviously all of this needs to be done in the correct order because one task maybe depends on the
other.
No, here I must mention something that a lot of people ask when it comes to terraform, and that is
what is a difference between Ansible and TerraForm, because they seem to be doing the same thing,
especially if you read the official definitions or official documentation.
They're sound like the same tools.
So the question is pretty logical.
What is the difference between them and which one should I use for my project?
So let's see the similarities and differences between these two using our example set up.
First of all, TerraForm and Ansible are both infrastructure as a code, meaning they're both used to
automate provisioning, configuring and managing the infrastructure.
However, TerraForm is mainly infrastructure provisioning tool.
That's where its main power lies.
But it also has possibilities to deploy applications in other tools on that infrastructure.
Ansible, on the other hand, is mainly a configuration tool.
So once the infrastructure is provisioned and it's there, Ansible can now be used to configure it and
deploy applications, install and update software on that infrastructure, etc..
So as you see, there are overlaps of what each tool does and this creates the confusion.
Other differences to consider in terms of those overlaps are Ansible is more mature and TerraForm is
relatively new.
And because of that it's also changing dynamically and TerraForm is much more advanced in orchestration.
So to summarize the difference, terraform is a better tool for provisioning infrastructure, and Ansible
is a better tool for configuring that infrastructure, deploying, installing applications and services
on them.
So it's a common practice where developers, engineers use the combination of these tools to cover the
whole set up end to end using both for their own strength instead of just using one tool.
So now let's go back to our use case where.
We created the infrastructure using TerraForm and on IWC provision successfully for your project and
you deployed the application on it.
Now we decide that you want to add five more servers to the existing infrastructure to deploy more micro
services because your team developed some more features and they need to be deployed.
And you also want to add some security configuration or maybe remove some stuff that you configure at
the beginning.
So now we are in the phase of managing the existing infrastructure, adding some stuff, reconfiguring,
removing some stuff, et cetera, and using terraform.
You can make such adjustments to infrastructure pretty easily.
And this task of managing the infrastructure is just as important, because once you've created the
initial infrastructure for your project, you will be continually adjusting and changing it.
And because of that, you also need some automation tool that will do most of the heavy lifting for
you so that you don't have to manually configure and do some stuff.
So once you are set up with TerraForm to create and change or maintain your infrastructure and other
useful thing or a common use case could be replicating that infrastructure.
Let's say after you have tested this set up and everything works fine, you decide now you want to release
your application in production environment.
So you want to create a production environment that replicates this exact setup and keep the first as
a development environment where you can test new features, new micro services and updates before you
launch it into production.
Again, you can use terraform here to automate that process so you can easily spin up an identical infrastructure
and set up using the same terraform code that you use for the first set up the development environment
setup, and you can do the same since we have an identical staging server as well.
So that makes these tasks also very easy.
So how does TerraForm do all this, how does he reform actually connect to this infrastructure provider
platforms and use all these technologies to provision stuff?
So, for example, how does TerraForm connect to enable us to create virtual space start?
Is it to instances, configure networking, et cetera, in order to do the job?
TerraForm has two main components that make up its architecture.
The first one is terraformed core and the core uses to input sources in order to do its job.
So we take Subform configuration that you as a user, right.
And where you define what needs to be created or provisioned.
And the second one is they're from state where TerraForm keeps them up to date, state of how the current
set up of the infrastructure looks like.
So what Cauthen does is it takes this inputs and he figures out the plan of what needs to be done.
So it compares the state.
What is the current state?
What is the configuration that you desire?
The end result, as I mentioned at the beginning, and compares that.
And when it sees there is a difference or you want something else, then what the current state is,
it figures out what needs to be done to get to the desired state in the configuration file.
So what needs to be created?
What needs to be updated, deleted in which order on that infrastructure set up in the second component
or the second part of the architecture are providers for specific technologies.
This could be cloud providers like it was Azure or other infrastructure as a service platforms.
So for the infrastructure level tasks.
But TerraForm, as I mentioned, has also providers for more high level components like cabernets or
other platform as a service tools, even some software as a service tool.
So it gives you possibility to create stuff on different levels like create an infrastructure, then
deploy or create communities on top of it, and then create services inside that or components inside
that this cluster.
So it gives you all these possibilities and it does it through those providers.
TerraForm has over 100 providers for these different technologies, and each provider then gives terraform
user access to its resources.
So through A.W. as provider, for example, you have access to hundreds of HWC resources like ISATOU
instances, database users, cetera.
With Karate's provider, you get access to these resources like services and deployments and name spaces,
etc. So this is how this works.
And This Way Terraformed tries to help you provision and cover the complete application set up from
infrastructure all the way to the application.
And this is sure convenient, but as I mentioned in the comparison between TerraForm and Ansible, terraformed
strength is actually in the infrastructure provisioning.
And for the other stuff, you can use Ansible or similar tools.
So once the core creates an execution plan based on the input from config, file and state, it then
uses providers for specific technologies to execute the plan to connect to those platforms and to actually
carry out those execution steps.
So now to also have an idea of how terraformed configuration file looks like, this is an example where
you see Aiwass provider is configured and through the provider, you now have to use a resource like
VPC.
You can create that with some attributes, the same way you have the Grenada's provider, you're configured.
And through that, now you can create a namespace resource where you have some attributes.
And the syntax is very intuitive.
I would say basically you define what you want.
You want a resource of a certain technology or certain provider created, and then you define its attributes.
And that's what TerraForm will create or do for you.
Now, one thing I mentioned the beginning and I want to go into detail is the declarative approach that
Terra forms configuration files are written in, and this is important to understand.
So what does declarative mean exactly when you create a terraformed file instead of defining what steps
to be executed, to create the BBC or to spin up five or two instances or create the network configuration,
you define the end stage you desire.
So you say, I want five servers with network configuration like this and I want one RWC user that has
these permissions to access all the servers.
TerraForm, go do that for me.
So instead of defining exactly what to do, which is an imperative approach, you define what the end
result should be.
A declarative approach now for the initial setup.
This may not make much difference.
So when you see the configuration of imperative and declarative approach, it might actually look pretty
similar.
But consider when you're updating your infrastructure, like removing a server or adding another server
or making other adjustments with imperative approach, you would say in a configuration file, remove
two servers, add a firewall configuration, ID some permissions to the AWEX user, etc. So you give
instructions of what to do with declarative approach.
Like in terraform example, you would say my new desired state is No.
Seven servers.
This firewall configuration and user with this set of permissions do whatever needs to be done to get
from the current state to the new desired state.
So now you don't have to actually calculate and decide how many service needs to be aired.
You just say, I want seven servers at the end.
That's what I want.
Or you don't need to calculate and figure out how many permissions or which permissions you should.
And you just say, I want this set of permissions to come out at the end.
So with the declarative approach, you just adjust the old configuration file and really execute it
instead of adding the new set of instructions.
This is obviously very comfortable because your configuration files stays clean and small.
But also you always know what the current setup is just by looking at the configuration file, because
that's always the end result.
Whereas in the first approach and imperative, you have to somehow set this up and figure out the delta
between all the changes applied by multiple instructions.
So you've created to terraform file configuration file that defines your desired infrastructure set
up on Adewusi.
Now how do you make TerraForm?
Take Action?
TerraForm has commands you can execute to go through different stages, which is pretty clear and straightforward.
The first command is refresh with this command terraformed will query the infrastructure provider in
our case HWC to get the up to date state.
So TerraForm will now know what is the current state of the infrastructure.
The next command is plen remember I said the Corps is responsible for taking current state in your configuration
file is input and decide based on the difference, what needs to be done.
That's the plan.
So what terraform needs to do in order to achieve the desired state that you define in the terraformed
configuration file?
If it's an initial set up, it figures out all the steps to create the desired set up.
If it's an update, it compares the existing set up with the new desired state and figures out what
changes and adjustments need to be made in which order to create the new desired state.
For example, add a new server, add a new permission, etc..
Now, this is just a plan.
This is where the core kind of constructs the the plan.
Logically, what needs to be done?
The next command is the command where the actual execution happens, and that's the apelike.
So with a play, you can execute the plan, so plan command is like a preview of what's going to happen
if you execute a play, obviously terraform in the background, will do the refresh, get the up to
date state, then create the plan and then apply it, which means if you want to execute a configuration
file, you can just execute their play command and it will do all this.
And another command is destroy, which obviously destroys the whole setup, removing elements one by
one in the right order and cleaning up all the resources that were created, basically reverting everything
that has been created.
And this could be used if, let's say, you create an environment for an important demo day and you
didn't want to interfere with the existing environments.
Once the demo is over, you can destroy the whole setup, destroy like apply will also check what's
currently running and then create a plan of what needs to be removed in which order.
So some of the key takeaways for TerraForm are, first of all, terraform is a tool for creating and
configuring infrastructure like virtual servers and so on, and then managing that infrastructure and
not for installing applications on these provision servers.
Second, terraform is a universal infrastructure as code tool.
So even if every cloud provider has their own infrastructure as code tools, if you have a multi cloud
infrastructure or a hybrid infrastructure like using your company's on premise servers and cloud servers,
you can use just one tool for all of these environments.
Instead of having teams for each environment, like one team managing the company's own data center
infrastructure, one team for EWR infrastructure and one for Google Cloud and so on.
And finally, because it integrates with many different technologies and platforms like Adewusi, Coronado's,
Jenkins, VMware and so on, you have one tool that you can use to talk to all these different technologies
and their APIs so you don't have to learn the API of each tool to talk to them.
So terraform abstracts that layer for you.
So now that you understand what TerraForm is and all of its benefits, let's actually get started using
terraform in practice.