Now, many of the best practices are Iran, TerraForm State and state file.
So let's quickly understand what they are.
First, TerraForm is a tool that automates creating infrastructure and then making changes and maintaining
that infrastructure and to keep track of the current infrastructure state and what changes you want
to make.
TerraForm uses state where you change configuration in TerraForm script.
It will compare your desired configuration with the current infrastructure state and figure out a plan
to make those desired changes in state.
In TerraForm is a simple Jason file, which looks like this and has a list of all the infrastructure
resources that TerraForm manages for you.
Because it's a simple Jason file.
Technically, you could make adjustments to the state file directly by manually changing stuff inside.
However, the first best practice is only change the state file contents through TerraForm Command execution
do not manually manipulate it.
Otherwise, you may get some unexpected results.
Now, where does this state file actually come from?
When you first execute terror form, apply command in TerraForm will automatically create the state
file locally.
But what if you're working in a tin?
So other team members also need to execute terror form commands, and they will also need the state
file for that.
In fact, every team member will need the latest state file before making their own updates.
So the second best practice is to configure a shared remote storage for the state file.
Every team member can now execute terror form commands using this shared state file.
In practice, remote storage beckoned for state file can be Amazon as three bucket tier form cloud is
your Google Cloud, etc. and you can configure TerraForm to use that remote storage as a state file
location.
But what if two team members execute TerraForm comments at the same time?
What happens to the state file when you have concurrent changes?
You might get a conflict or mess up your state file to avoid changing TerraForm State at the same time.
We have the next best practice, which is locking the state file until an update is fully completed
and then unlock it for the next command.
This way, you can prevent concurrent edits to your state file.
In practice, you will have this configured in your storage.
Bequant in as three bucket.
For example, Dynamo DBE service is automatically used for state file locking.
But note that not all storage beckons.
Support this.
So be aware of that when choosing a remote storage for the state file.
If supported, TerraForm will lock your state file automatically.
Now what happens if you lose your state file, something may happen to your remote storage location
or someone may accidentally overwrite the data.
Or it may get corrupted to avoid this, the next best practice is to backup your state file.
In practice, you can do this by enabling versioning for it.
In many, storage beacons will have such a feature like in S3 Bucket, for example, you can simply
turn on the versioning feature.
This also means that you have a nice history of state changes, and you can reverse to any previous
TerraForm State if you want to.
Great, so now you have your state filed in a shared remote location with locking enabled and file versioning
for backup.
So you have one state file for your infrastructure, but usually you have multiple environments like
development, testing and production.
So which environment does this state file belong to?
Can you manage all the environments with one state file?
And this is the next best practice to use one dedicated state file per environment, and each state
file will have its own storage backend with locking and versioning configured.
This were best practices related to TerraForm State.
The next three best practices are about how to manage the TerraForm code itself and how to apply infrastructure
changes.
These practices can be grouped into a relatively new trend that emerged in the infrastructure as code
space, which is called get ups.
So let's see the next best practices.
When you're working on TerraForm scripts in a team, it's important to share the code in order to collaborate
effectively.
So as the next best practice, you should actually host TerraForm code in its own kit repository, just
like your application code.
This is not only beneficial for effective collaboration in a team, but you also get versioning for
your infrastructure code changes so you can have a history of changes in your TerraForm code.
Now, who is allowed to make changes to TerraForm code?
Can anyone just directly commit the changes to the repository?
The best practice is actually to treat your TerraForm code just like your application code.
This means you should have the same process of reviewing and testing the changes in your infrastructure
code as you have for your application code with a continuous integration pipeline.
Using Merge requests to integrate code changes.
This will allow your team to collaborate and produce quality infrastructure code, which is tested and
reviewed.
Great, so you have tested and reviewed code changes in your repository.
Now how do you apply them to the actual infrastructure?
Because eventually you want to update your infrastructure with those changes, right?
The final best practice is to execute TerraForm commence to apply changes in a continuous deployment
pipeline.
So instead of team members manually updating the infrastructure by executing terraform commands from
their own computers, it should happen only from an automated built.
This way, you have a single location from which all the infrastructure changes happen and you have
a more streamlined process of updating your infrastructure.
These are the eight TerraForm best practices you can apply to make your TerraForm projects more robust
and easier to work on as a team.