Now is a first step we need to install TerraForm locally so we can start using it, and obviously based
on which operating system you're using, the installation will be a bit different.
So either you can install it using a package manager tool on Linux or make or you can just download
TerraForm Binary from TerraForm official page and then set it up locally yourself.
And this applies to Windows, Linux and Mic, and you will find links to how to install TerraForm on
different operating systems.
In the video description So check it out there and do the installation on your OS.
And once you have TerraForm, then you can move on with the tutorial.
Now, if you're on, make the easiest way to install.
TerraForm is using Prew package manager used to brew install tier form.
And this will install TerraForm, and once you have it installed, then you can use TerraForm version.
And if you have an output of TerraForm version, it means it is correctly installed and configured.
Since TerraForm is widely used to automate energy use infrastructure, and because E.W. is is the most
popular cloud platform out there, we will use IWC as an example to learn all TerraForm concepts.
However, note that all these will be very similar to using TerraForm for other platforms and technologies.
In this part, I'm going to show you how to write TerraForm File that connects to your A.W. account,
and we will create a VPC and subnet in our account just to learn the basic concepts of TerraForm and
its syntax.
So the first thing we need is we're going to create a project folder called TerraForm.
So let's create a folder called TerraForm,
and we're going to start creating files in that folder.
Now that's actually open visual studio code and create a new file here.
And let's say it into our TerraForm folder that we just created.
And let's call it Main Dot Taf T.f, since whatever form and main is just the name we give.
You can name it whatever you want.
This is just a standard for calling the main TerraForm file window to t.f.
So let's create this file.
And if you're working in Visual Studio, you can actually install a plugin for TerraForm.
There is actually the official one from Hershey Corp TerraForm.
However, I have installed another one, which actually looks pretty good because of syntax highlighting.
But whichever plugin you want, just install one so that we have a nice syntax highlighting in our file.