For this course, you're going to need an eyewitness account, and in order to create an account, you
basically just have to fill out some forms, including your address, information, credit card information
and so on, because AWB wants to make sure that people who are creating accounts are verified and are
registering with valid data.
And I will put a link below for a guide of how to create an account that you can follow.
And once you have an account, you get a free tier offer from either.
Yes.
So what does it actually mean on AWB documentation?
You have this free page that basically lists all the components, all the services of AWB that you can
use for free for one year after registering an account.
And some of them or some of the most important ones are the easy to instance, which is the virtual
server, which we're going to be creating on areas as well as some storage and so on.
So you can take advantage of that, free your account on areas.
Now, by default, when you create an account on us, you have a route user.
This user gets created automatically and this user has access to all the services and all the features.
So it has unlimited privileges to do whatever you want in your account, including the billing Pardes
account settings and so on.
So the first thing we want to do when the account is registered is create an admin user that has less
privileges than route user, but it will have all the privileges that we need to create.
Easy to instance, deploy some applications on that.
And this is the first thing that Adewusi also advises to do for security reasons.
So if you go inside the I am service, you will see the configuration dashboard so we can create users,
groups and permissions here and manage all the stuff here.
Now, admin user can also have permission to create users, assign the roles to them and so on, so
you can have one admin user to manage and administer the whole account, but it will still have less
privileges than the road user.
For example, it will not be able to access the billing and credit card information.
And then using that admin user, you can actually create other users and give them other permissions
for team members.
For example, if you have a database team that all use NWS and configure stuff in there, obviously
you need to give them all permissions and access to AC2 and maybe some other services so the admin user
can be the one that administers all of this.
So now let's create a user admin that has admin privileges to do stuff on Aiwass services, we don't
need a group for that because it's just going to be one user and the only one with admin access.
So let's create it.
So here we have an end user button.
Let's call it admin and we can give the user two types of access.
Could be either Xs through the console in the UI.
So basically you can log in on the UI and then do stuff through the UI like configure stuff, change
stuff and so on.
And you can also have programmatic access.
This is when you can execute different tasks from your command line and this can be either through a
command line interface or in our case, we're going to use terraformed commands to access HWC.
So we need programmatic access for the admin user to execute terraformed commands.
And you can decide whether a user has one of those EXIS types or maybe both.
In this case, we can give admin both types of access because we want to be able to access the UI console
with it.
So we want to be able to log in with this user but also execute things from command line.
And as you see, the management console EXIS display some other options, because if we are going to
log in with this user, we need a password for the user as well, and we can let it all generate a password.
And with this option, we can force the user, the admin user on the first login to reset their password.
So the UI access will basically be through username and password username here, password, auto generated
and the programatic access will be the keys.
So from the command line, we're going to need exis keys or secret access key to log into Adewusi and
then execute some commands.
Let's go to next.
Now here we can create a group that the user can be part of.
It is actually the best practice to have all the users in a group and then to assign the permissions
to the group rather than directly to user.
But the admin user is going to be the only one in the group so we can actually skip creation of group
so we can assign a permission to the user directly.
And for that we are going to go to attach existing policies directly.
And this is a list of all the permissions or all the policies that we can choose from.
And this is a pretty long list because you have granular permission policies in us.
So you can basically decide for each single service what type of Xs you want to grant a user.
And this actually is good because it supports the best practice of giving the user the least privilege
they need.
So if a user needs the Read-Only permission for a service, you can give a user read-only permission
rather than full access.
So admin user is going to get administrator access, which basically includes all the policies and all
the permissions that are needed for administering your account.
So we're going to choose administrator access policy and go to the next page.
You can also add text to the user, which is basically additional information like metadata about the
user, if these are individual team members in your organization.
This could be an email address, description or job title, name, surname, etc..
It's optional, though.
And we're going to skip this for admin user.
And next and this is our summary page.
So we have created an admin user.
We're giving it access to login through a Web console.
The password will be generated as well as programmatic access from the command line interface, and
it has administrator access privileges.
So all the permissions it needs to administer the account, let's create the user.
And here you have all the information, all the secret information as well for the user, so password,
you're going to need this one to log in to the console.
And these two are the keys to access the US account and the services from EDWYN user from your command
line.
So save all this information and those keys securely.
So download this file and we're going to reference that later.
And as a next step, we're going to log into UI using this password and change the password because
we have configured it this way.
So let's sign out as a road user and log in with the Edman user again.
Log back in and in the signing page, you have a selection between route user and I am user, let's
choose this one.
The ID or account idea of your user is also in this downloaded file.
If you open it in the console, in link, you have this ID here, you can use a link directly to go
to the login page.
Like this and this I.D. is going to be filled automatically, so this is the account, Edem.
And here you have the username, we called it admin and the password, which is also in this file.
And since we've configured it, we have to change the password.
And as you see, we're locked in as admin user and we can configure services and do stuff now with admin
user.
A quick note here that AWB is actually changing the UI very often, also in real time for different
users.
So the UI that you are seeing in my video can actually be different from what you are seeing right now,
but most of the structure should be the same.
So, for example, if I go into easy to you see that I have this toggle new, easy to experience enabled.
So a couple of things have changed in this UI and it may look different from yours.
So do not get confused by that.
It may happen pretty often.