Now, when you're working with TerraForm in a team where basically different team members may be executed,
terraformed comments locally or you're integrating terraformed in a SkyCity pipeline, you have multiple
places where state can be created.
Right.
So, for example, if we execute TerraForm Applied from Jenkins' Pipeline, it would create the terraformed
state file on Jenkins'.
So the terraformed state file would be only available inside the jenkins' server.
So we don't have access to it locally.
So if I wanted to do TerraForm applied locally to apply some changes on top of that, Tearfund will
actually try to create everything again because it will think that I am starting from an empty or fresh
state, basically.
So how do we actually share the terraformed state between different environments, maybe different team
members?
And there is actually a very simple way to do that.
And it's also a best practice is to configure a remote terraformed state.
So basically a remote storage where this terraformed state file will be stored.
It's also good for data backup in case something happens to the server and the state file basically
gets removed.
Right.
So to storage in a remote place, security is actually a good way to do that.
So how do we configure a remote storage for TerraForm State file?