Now, there are many cases where you need to execute some sort of commands or maybe a shell script on
the virtual servers that you have provisioned with TerraForm, and this is just one of the examples
of executing commands on that easy to server that we just provisioned by passing in.
The user data is sort of initial data to be executed on the server in many of the cloud providers like
A.W. as Google Cloud is here and so on, they actually support this attribute to hand over basically
some initial execution commands or maybe a file, a script file here for they created the VM to be executed.
However, it is important to differentiate here again that all this data or these commands or script
to be executed will basically be handed over from terraformed to the cloud provider.
So once the SC two instances created by TerraForm and TerraForm gets a status of ISATOU created, basically
returns the status to us and we see that in in the come in line is everything was created successfully
and the output.
However, TerraForm doesn't wait for the virtual machine to be initialized.
So basically terraformed job is done at this point.
And once the server gets initialized, the cloud provider in this case, Adewusi, will then execute
these commands on that initialised server.
So this is how it works.
So basically, TerraForm doesn't have any control over what's going to happen next or how these commands
will be executed.
And if one of these commands actually fail and for example, Docker Run doesn't work because Docker
wasn't properly installed or some permission or whatever happens there, then TerraForm will not know
anything about the error.
So we won't get that information without access into the server and then debugging it.
So that's important to know that even though we are able to pass on the data or initial comments to
configure the server, it is actually not in terraformed control anymore.
Now, with that said, there are still ways to execute commands, execute scripts from TerraForm.
And it is important to mention that because TerraForm has its own concept of parameters for executing
commands and scripts on virtual machines.
And it's good to know what these concepts are, how they're used and what it's about.