And we can actually do this in a new branch.
So from the current branch, we're going to create a new branch called Feature Slash Provisioners and
we're going to switch to that branch and we're in this new branch, Provisioners And now we can add
all the code in here.
So as I said, there is an alternative to executing the commands or a script on a remote server using
a provisioner called
remote.
Exec.
So remote exec is basically a provisioner that allows us to connect to the remote server and execute
commands on that server.
Right.
And the way we can define commands here is using inline, which basically lets us define a list of commands
to be executed on a remote server.
For example, we can export variables here.
We can say environment dev doesn't really matter.
And we can have a bunch of different comments here.
We can also create a directory or even install some programs, right?
So basically, any command that you want to execute, you can do it using a remote exec provisioner.
And with inline attribute, you can list all the commands like this.
Right.
So all of these will be executed on the AWS instance that is going to be created.
Now, whenever we define a remote exec provisioner, we actually have to tell TerraForm how to connect
to that remote server.
And even though we are in this instance a resource inside, it doesn't actually by default connect to
that server.
So we need to define the connection explicitly to connect to this remote server and we can do that using
connection attribute for provisioner.
This is specific to provisioner by the way.
It actually belongs to it.
And in the connection we have the type, we have two types of connection.
We have SSH and win M the default actually being the SSH type.
And then we have the host So we basically have to tell TerraForm the remote server address.
And since we are inside the AWS instance and this is the server we are connecting to, we can actually
use something called self and self is like, you know, in programming languages, you have this to
refer to the current context.
In our case, self refers to the object or the resource that we are in.
And since we are in resource AWS instance Self will refer to this object right here and on self.
Then we can get the public IP attribute like this.
And then we need username which is EC2 user on EC2 instance and then we have the private key.
You can also have password if you're connecting using username and password, but you can also pass
in the private key, which you can also do by referring to a file.
So we can do private.
Key location, just like we did for Public Key.
And.
And the private key is ID, RSA.
Private.
Okay.
So basically this.
Block here will be able to connect TerraForm to the remote server using the SSH connection in order
to execute these commands on it.
So the difference is that here we're just passing on the data to EC2 or to AWS actually so that it can
execute all these commands there.
In our case, we're switching into the server and executing the commands there using TerraForm.
So let's actually try this out.
So I'm going to do a TerraForm plan.
And it will show us that everything needs to be created because I have deleted all my resources and
we can now do TerraForm apply?
So as you see all these resources got created and here you see the output for the remote exec provisioner
and you see that connection was established right here, connected with all these parameters and now
we can actually ssh into the server.
And here if I do ls we have a new directory.
However, for a more realistic use case, you may want to execute a script on the remote server like
we did in here.
And there is a script attribute for that.
So instead of inline.
Attribute.
We have script.
And then we have the value, which is the name of the file that we want to execute.
And we have this entry script file that we want to execute.
And we can provide it like this directly.
And this block now will basically take the entry script that we have on our local machine.
And this script will be copied to the remote resource and execute it there.
So TerraForm will actually take this and copy it to the EC2 instance and it will execute the script
there.
So basically all the commands that we see here will be executed.
And I actually added this command here just to make sure that the changes to the Docker group, Docker
user group will be applied.
So when we add the user to the user group called Docker, we need to restart the Docker so that it loads
that change so that we can then execute Docker without sudo.
So that's how the remote exec provisioner actually works.
And we actually have two other provisioner types.
Another one is called Local Exec.
So it's going to be provisioner instead of remote exec.
We have local exec and local exec is basically commands that will be executed locally.
So we're going to have a command attribute and we can execute any command like we would directly by
typing it on our local computer.
If you want it to print out the public IP address of this server right here, you could do self.
Public IP and this will basically echo it.
We can also save it into a file.
And this will get executed locally on our machine.
So that's the local exec.
And the third one is called file provisioner.
And it's also pretty straightforward, actually.
Let me show you an example of that.
So we have provisioner called file.
And the purpose of this provision is basically to copy files from the local machine to the remote machine.
So whenever we have any maybe configuration files or whatever files that we need on the server, we
can actually copy them from wherever TerraForm script is running to the remote resource.
And for that we have a source.
So basically, what are we copying?
So, for example, I don't know if we want to copy a script or a Readme file, it doesn't matter.
We're going to provide that path to the file.
Let's do an example with N3 Scripts SH file and then we're going to have a destination obviously on
the remote machine.
And this will be a location on the, in this case, EC2 machine where the file will be copied to.
So the home directory of EC2 user.
And then whatever file name we want to give it so it can be the same like this, or we can even give
it another name.
Like this, for example.
So this provisioner will take the local file and copy it to the remote destination with this name.
So these are the three provisioner types that we have.
And the file provisioner also needs the connection block because obviously it needs to connect to the
remote machine to copy the file on that machine.
So these two provisioners remote exec and file Provisioners actually need a connection block to connect
to the remote server.
And local exec is just executed locally, so it doesn't need to connect to a remote resource.
Now, when you're working with TerraForm, there are actually a lot of use cases and scenarios where
you would want to execute some stuff remotely on your servers, right?
There are things to configure their applications and software to be installed and so on.