And you might think that provisionals are a great way of executing those use cases.
However, if we go to the provisional documentation of terraformed here, you see that it says provisions
are a last resort and this is just the headline.
But Terraformed actually highlights the fact that provisions are a sort of a workaround.
If you absolutely have to use terraform in order to execute scripts and execute commands on your provision
infrastructure.
However, it is not recommended and it is not something that TerraForm advises to do.
So here it says that there are lots of use cases and situations where provisions can be used.
However, there are better solutions and we do not recommend using provisions for any of the use cases
described in the following sections.
Now there is actually or there are actually good reasons for why terrorism doesn't recommend using provisions
and why you shouldn't be using them.
Just generally speaking, provisions do not work very well.
Right.
So there might be some unexpected behavior or some parts of the script or command may not actually execute
and you may have some problems.
So from my experience, it doesn't actually work that well.
So I would personally also not suggest using a remote exec, for example, in order to remotely execute
the comments on an instance.
So user data, if it's available for that specific cloud provider for us, for example.
It is and available attribute is much better to use as sort of an initial script or initial command
to be executed on the virtual machine instead of using the remote exec.
However, there are actual reasons why Terraformed itself doesn't actually recommend using provisionals.
First of all, provisionary concept actually breaks the concept of IDE impotency in terraform in item
potency.
If you remember, it is a word that describes something that always gives you the same output no matter
how many times you execute a command.
So when we do terraform apply with the same exact configuration, it always gives us the same output.
So the problem with provisions is that because we're using scripts that are just basic shell scripts
or shell commands that are not actually part of TerraForm itself, TerraForm has no way of knowing what
you are executing in that script.
Terraformed doesn't know or has no way of knowing whether these commands actually executed successfully.
What is the current state or if we change something in here?
TerraForm cannot tell whether this change actually deviates from the current state.
So what needs to be actually done in order to apply the changes that you made in your commands or in
your Shell script?
So it kind of breaks the tear forms concept of how the current state and the desired state comparison
happens, how TerraForm calculates the difference between the two in order to decide what action is
to be taken and also terraformed.
Cannot control the way you write those scripts, write the scripts themselves may not be as important
like TerraForm is.
So for these use cases, they're actually alternatives that TerraForm also recommends using and they're
also best practices.
So first of all, if you want to execute commands remotely or configure a remote server, you actually
should use some configuration management tool.
Could be Chev or Puppet Ansible sold.
There are actually multiple tools out there.
So basically what you can do is once the server is provisioned with terraform, you can hand over the
process to one of those configuration management tools.
So using terraform you can pass the Init data or some initial data to this config manager tool and then
config manager basically takes over and configures the server and does all the stuff that it can do
because the config manager tools have more visibility inside the VM and they can actually compare the
state and they can actually manage and control how the things get executed there while terraformed,
cannot do this.
As for the local exec, if you want to locally create files, for example, there is a provider called
Loku that is maintained by Hoshide Corp and.
This is a recommended way of handling local files in TerraForm, the local provider, which is for handling
local files, and you have a bunch of configuration in here.
So advantage of using local provider instead of local exec will be that the provider actually has a
way of comparing if something changed and with the current and desired states are so we can detect the
changes.
So the declarative model is kind of maintained this way.
And as for any type of other script execution, generally, whether it's copying files to the remote
or executing some scripts instead of using the configuration manager, especially if you're building
this whole thing up, using a suicide pipeline where you integrate, terraform, you can actually execute
this script as a separate part from Jenkins' or your SkyCity tool instead of having it executed using
terraformed.
So I hope this makes clear that provisionary is actually a workaround for most of the use cases where
you need to execute some code, either locally or remotely or copy files to it.
And it is actually not a recommended way of doing it.
However, if you still come across provisionary, maybe in somebody else's terraformed config file,
you should know what the concept is and what it does and how it can be used.
And one final note on parishioners is that if provision or fails, for example, if you forgot to copy
the script and if it's not found on a remote machine and the file cannot be executed, then terraformed
will actually taint or mark the resource where the provisionary is getting executed is failed.
So we have to recreate it, actually.
So even though the easy two incidents may get created initialised, you will get an error status from
TerraForm and the easy to instance will be marked for deletion.
So if I believe this.
And we do terraform, employ.
And here is a see, we have an error message that the file could not be open because the file doesn't
exist on remote and basically we don't have any success output, even though the instance has been created
and it is being initialized now.